<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Samuel de Korte</title>
        <link>http://localhost:3000</link>
        <description>Your blog description</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 16:27:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Plans for 2025]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/plans-for-2025</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/plans-for-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[As we step into 2025, it’s the perfect time to share what lies ahead for this year.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What are the plans for 2025? As we step into 2025, it’s the perfect time to share what lies ahead for this year. Here’s an overview of my upcoming projects and plans:</p>
<h2 id="the-452nd-anti-aircraft-artillery-battalion-destroyers-of-the-luftwaffe-and-jim-crow-will-be-published">The 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion: Destroyers of the Luftwaffe and Jim Crow will be published!</h2>
<p>The book on the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion will be available in March 2025 in the UK and EU, while the book will become available in May 2025 in the US. Pre-orders for both books are available through the websites of the publishers: <a href="https://www.pen-and-sword.co.uk/The-452nd-Anti-Aircraft-Artillery-Battalion-Hardback/p/52031">Pen and Sword</a> and <a href="https://www.casematepublishers.com/9781399032100/the-452nd-anti-aircraft-artillery-battalion/">Casemate</a>. The battalion, which fought as part of General Patton’s Third Army, fought valiantly in Europe during the Second World War and their history deserves much more attention than it has received so far.</p>
<div class="flex flex-col items-center justify-center text-center"><img alt="The cover of the book 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion: Destroyers of the Luftwaffe and Jim Crow. The book is written by Samuel de Korte." loading="lazy" width="404" height="602" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 200px)" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F452nd-antiaircraft-artillery-battalion.d0b14f1f.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/><figcaption><b>The cover of the book 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion: Destroyers of the Luftwaffe and Jim Crow. (2025)</b></figcaption></div>
<p>I’m particularly glad that I got in touch with the family of Stafford Rimes, a soldier of the battalion who was killed in combat, and we have included an image of him in the book. You can also view it <a href="/veterans">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="the-777th-field-artillery-battalion">The 777th Field Artillery Battalion</h2>
<p>Progress continues on my project about the 777th Field Artillery Battalion. While I can’t set a publication date just yet, I’m in the final stages of writing. As always, history can be full of surprises, so I’ll take the time needed to ensure accuracy and depth. Until this project is complete, I’ll focus on just this one. Once that’s completed, I’ll think about the next book.</p>
<h2 id="the-world-war-ii-daily-podcast">The World War II Daily Podcast</h2>
<p>Together with Pietro Deserti, I co-host the World War II Daily Podcast. You can listen to it on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4DOxOOi0S3cxcMjms6Mq0M">Spotify</a> or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@TheWorldWarIIDailyPodcast">YouTube</a>. We release episodes monthly, on the last Friday of each month, offering expert insights into World War II history. Upcoming episodes include an interview with <a href="https://lipstickandwar.com/">Molly Sampson</a>, the history consultant for the <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt24458622/">Netflix</a> film about the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion, and a discussion on the Brazilian Expeditionary Forces with <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Store-Cesar-Campiani-Maximiano/s?rh=n%3A133140011%2Cp_27%3ACesar%2BCampiani%2BMaximiano">Cesar Campiani Maximiano</a>. Stay tuned for these fascinating stories!</p>
<h2 id="other-projects-the-651st-motor-ambulance-company-and-the-clean-wehrmacht-myth">Other projects: The 651st Motor Ambulance Company and the Clean Wehrmacht myth</h2>
<p>I have recently acquired a photo album of Willie M. Jackson, who was the First Sergeant of the 651st Motor Ambulance Company, which was previously known as the 651st Ambulance Company Motor. He also served in the 708th Medical Sanitary Company. The album provides rare glimpses into the daily lives of soldiers, who served in Italy during World War Two. For example, there are photographs of Black American soldiers taking care of their ambulances or just doing their duties. Unfortunately, not a lot is known about these units, and not many records seem to remain of these two units. That makes research difficult, but I’d love to know more about him, his units, and his service! It’s a project that needs to be developed further.</p>
<p>Additionally, I’ve noticed increasing misrepresentation of history on social media, particularly regarding the “Clean Wehrmacht” myth and the &quot;non-political history&quot; fallacy. These narratives deny the Wehrmacht&#x27;s involvement in war crimes or attempt to separate military actions from political ideology. I plan to address these misconceptions in future articles to ensure historical accuracy prevails.</p>
<h2 id="which-project-will-i-work-on-after-the-777th-field-artillery-battalion">Which project will I work on after the 777th Field Artillery Battalion?</h2>
<p>There are several units I’m considering writing about after the 777th Field Artillery Battalion project. I have not decided yet, but I’m inclined to research the 969th Field Artillery Battalion. This unit, which has a remarkable history, certainly deserves more credit than they have received thus far. It was the first Black American unit that in its entirety received the Presidential Unit Citation, which they earned for their valiant stand at Bastogne during the Battle of the Bulge in December 1944 and January 1945 alongside the 101st Airborne Division.</p>
<p>So that’s all for now. Be sure to follow me on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/samuel.dekorte/">Instagram</a> and if you have another question, send me a message!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion: Heroic Black American soldiers during World War II]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/the-614th-tank-destroyer-battalion</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/the-614th-tank-destroyer-battalion</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion is one of the most outstanding Black American units to serve during World War II. Formed during an era of segregation in the U.S. Army, this battalion proved that valor, skill, and determination knew no racial boundaries. Their extraordinary accomplishments on the battlefield helped pave the way for the eventual desegregation of the military and solidified their place in the annals of African American military history.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion: Heroes of World War II</p>
<p>The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion is one of the most outstanding Black American units to serve during World War II. Formed during an era of segregation in the U.S. Army, this battalion proved that valor, skill, and determination knew no racial boundaries. Their extraordinary accomplishments on the battlefield helped pave the way for the eventual desegregation of the military and solidified their place in the annals of African American military history.</p>
<img alt="An image of soldiers of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion standing around a three inch gun. The image is taken in the year 1945." loading="lazy" width="4802" height="4703" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftd61401.d547e563.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>A photograph of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion and their primary weapon: the 3-inch gun. (1945) (Courtesy of United States Army Heritage and Education Center)</em></p>
<p>Activated in 1942, the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion was part of the U.S. Army’s broader strategy to counter the formidable German tank forces. The unit trained extensively in anti-tank warfare, mastering the use of their towed anti-tank guns. By 1944, they were deployed to Europe.</p>
<h3 id="the-battle-of-climbach">The Battle of Climbach</h3>
<p>The battalion’s defining moment came during its advance through Nazi-occupied Europe. On December 14, 1944, in the town of Climbach, France, the 614th achieved a remarkable victory against a heavily fortified German position. During this engagement, First Lieutenant Charles L. Thomas, the commander of Company C, displayed extraordinary heroism. Leading Third Platoon during the engagement, he deployed his guns on the reverse slope outside of town. Despite his injuries, he continued to lead his soldiers, until another officer was present to take over. His actions initially earned him the Distinguished Service Cross. Later this was upgraded to the Medal of Honor, which was awarded posthumously in 1997.
For its performance, Third Platoon, Company C, the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion became the first Black American unit to receive the Distinguished Unit Citation. This recognition was a testament to their tactical expertise, discipline, and unyielding courage under fire.</p>
<h3 id="black-and-white-soldiers">Black and white soldiers</h3>
<p>Their story, however, goes beyond battlefield heroism. As participants in the “Double Victory” campaign, the men of the 614th fought not only against fascism abroad but also against the systemic racism and discrimination that pervaded the U.S. society. Their success challenged prevailing prejudices and played a significant role in shaping the postwar push for racial equality. Many white soldiers of the 103rd Infantry Division, to which the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion had been attached for most of their combat career, came home with changed ideas of race and equality.
The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion’s legacy endures today, as a symbol of excellence, sacrifice, and patriotism. Their contributions to World War II demonstrated the critical role of Black American soldiers in the Allied victory and inspired the eventual desegregation of the U.S. armed forces in 1948. Today, their story reminds us of the resilience and bravery of those who fought for a nation that did not fully recognize their worth—a powerful testament to their enduring fight for equality.</p>
<h3 id="more-images-available">More Images Available</h3>
<p>If you wish to see more photographs of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion, check out my <a href="/images">image section</a> where you can view them.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 761st Tank Battalion and their unit history “Come Out Fighting!”]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/761st-tank-battalion</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/761st-tank-battalion</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The 761st Tank Battalion, famously known as the "Black Panthers," holds a distinguished place in the history of World War II as the first Black American tank unit to see combat. Activated in 1942, the battalion operated under the rallying cry “Come Out Fighting!”, a motto that reflected their determination to overcome not only the Axis powers but also the pervasive racism and segregation within the U.S. military.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-761st-tank-battalion-the-black-panthers-of-world-war-ii">The 761st Tank Battalion: The Black Panthers of World War II</h2>
<p>The 761st Tank Battalion, famously known as the &quot;Black Panthers,&quot; holds a distinguished place in the history of World War II as the first Black American tank unit to see combat. Activated in 1942, the battalion operated under the rallying cry “Come Out Fighting!”, a motto that reflected their determination to overcome not only the Axis powers but also the pervasive racism and segregation within the U.S. military.</p>
<img alt="A tank of the 761st Tank Battalion." loading="lazy" width="5387" height="4444" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px)" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76101.1b3e0dd4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>A tank of the 761st Tank Battalion (Courtesy of National Archives and Records Administration).</em><br/>
Attached to General Patton’s Third Army, the 761st entered combat in November 1944 during the Lorraine Campaign in France. Their skill and resilience quickly earned them recognition as a formidable force. Over 183 days of continuous combat, the battalion played pivotal roles in major operations, including the relief of Bastogne during the Battle of the Bulge and the crossing of the Rhine River into Germany. Despite heavy losses, they consistently demonstrated exceptional bravery, tactical expertise, and discipline on the battlefield.</p>
<h2 id="the-black-panthers">The Black Panthers</h2>
<p>One of the battalion&#x27;s most significant contributions was its ability to adapt to challenging conditions. Fighting in harsh winter weather and against entrenched German forces, the Black Panthers proved their mettle in both offensive and defensive operations. Their actions directly contributed to the liberation of towns, the capture of enemy strongholds, and the eventual defeat of Nazi Germany.<br/>
Despite their exemplary service, the men of the 761st faced racism from their own ranks and were often denied the recognition they deserved. It wasn’t until 1978 that the battalion received a Presidential Unit Citation, honoring their extraordinary heroism. Notable members, such as Staff Sergeant Ruben Rivers, who was posthumously awarded the Medal of Honor for his sacrifice. Other notable members include Warren Crecy, who was nicknamed “the baddest man in the 761st Tank Battalion”.</p>
<img alt="A tank of the 761st Tank Battalion is crossing a Bailey Bridge near the town of Vic-Sur-Seille, France, as it moves to the frontline." loading="lazy" width="3376" height="2450" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px)" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbp76103.d34d6d72.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>A tank of the 761st Tank Battalion is crossing a Bailey Bridge near the town of Vic-Sur-Seille, France, as it moves to the frontline (9 November 1944) (Courtesy of National Archives and Records Administration).</em></p>
<h2 id="come-out-fighting">Come Out Fighting</h2>
<p>The legacy of the 761st Tank Battalion endures as a symbol of courage, determination, and the fight for equality. Their story reminds us of the critical contributions of Black soldiers in securing victory during World War II, even as they battled for their rightful place in history.</p>
<p>Part of securing their legacy comes from their unit history “Come Out Fighting”, which was written by Trezzvant Anderson. He was a reporter, who had covered a lot of the exploits of the 761st Tank Battalion. The book was published in 1945 and available online.</p>
<p>Want to download the unit history and read it yourself? Click <a href="/sources">here</a> to check out the sources.</p>
<p>Want to help my research? Check out my Patreon <a href="https://www.patreon.com/samueldekorte/about?l=en">here</a>. As a thank you, you&#x27;ll receive a monthly postcard featuring Black American soldiers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Source Shared: Speech Helen Douglas]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/helen-douglas</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/helen-douglas</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Helen Gahagan Douglas, an ardent advocate for equality and justice, delivered a speech during World War II celebrating the vital contributions of Black American soldiers. Her speech is titled: “The Negro Soldier: A partial record of Negro devotion and heroism in the cause of freedom gathered from the files of the War and Navy Departments” and delivered in January 1946 before the House of Representatives. Her words highlight the courage and resilience of Black Americans in the fight against global tyranny.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="helen-gahagan-douglas-and-the-negro-soldier-celebrating-black-contributions-in-wwii">Helen Gahagan Douglas and The Negro Soldier: Celebrating Black Contributions in WWII</h2>
<p>Helen Gahagan Douglas, an ardent advocate for equality and justice, delivered a speech during World War II celebrating the vital contributions of Black American soldiers. Her speech is titled: “The Negro Soldier: A partial record of Negro devotion and heroism in the cause of freedom gathered from the files of the War and Navy Departments” and delivered in January 1946 before the House of Representatives. Her words highlight the courage and resilience of Black Americans in the fight against global tyranny.</p>
<img alt="An image of Helen Gahagan Douglas taken around the year 1945." loading="lazy" width="2509" height="3157" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fdouglas.5a5b4389.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>A photograph of Helen Gahagan Douglas, dated circa 1945. (Public Domain)</em><br/>
The speech is well researched and serves as powerful reminders that Black American soldiers were not only instrumental on the battlefield but also represented the ideals of democracy and freedom. From the legendary Tuskegee Airmen in the skies to the brave infantrymen of the 92nd Infantry Division, Douglas emphasized how these men risked their lives for a country that had yet to grant them full equality. Other famous mentioned units are the 761st Tank Battalion, widely known as the &quot;Black Panthers”, the 450th Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion, and the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion.</p>
<h3 id="stories-of-valor-and-courage">Stories of valor and courage</h3>
<p>These stories of valor and unity were meant to inspire both Black and white Americans to stand together. Douglas’s speech extended this mission, reinforcing the need for postwar recognition of civil rights. She called attention to the ongoing &quot;Double Victory&quot; campaign—a fight for victory over fascism abroad and racism at home—using the bravery of Black soldiers to challenge systemic discrimination.</p>
<p>At a time when the military remained segregated, this message resonated deeply and several people wrote to her to congratulate her on her speech. Her words in the speech continue to remind us of the critical role Black Americans played in shaping history.</p>
<p>These days, for any reader wishing to get a broad overview of the contributions of Black American soldiers in the Second World War, this is an excellent place to start. Many units and individual stories of heroism are described. She effectively advocates for a better recognition of the participation of Black Americans.</p>
<h3 id="source-available">Source available</h3>
<p>Eager to read the full speech of Helen Gahagan Douglas for yourself? Head on over to the <a href="/sources">sources section</a> where you can download a copy of it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/6888th-central-postal-directory-battalion</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/6888th-central-postal-directory-battalion</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion holds a unique place in American military history as the only all-Black, all-female unit deployed during World War II. The battalion was comprised of 855 women, many of whom were members of the Women’s Army Corps (WAC). They faced not only the challenges of military service but also the pervasive racism and sexism of the era. Their primary mission was to sort and deliver mail, which was backlogged due to the war. The unit was stationed in Birmingham, England, where they quickly went to work, processing over 17 million pieces of mail during their deployment.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img alt="Women of the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion in France. In the middle is Major Charity Adams. She is ordering a cola." caption="Women of the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion in France. In the middle is Major Charity Adams. She is ordering a cola." loading="lazy" width="5547" height="4329" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 200px)" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th01.a0f1f8a0.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<figcaption align="center"><b>In Rouen, France, Second Lieutenant Freda le Beau (New Orleans, LA), post exchange officer, serves the first Coca Cola to Major Charity Adams (Columbia, South Carolina), at the grand opening of the WAC battalion&#x27;s new snack bar. (Courtesy of NARA: NAID: 175539159)</b></figcaption>
<img alt="Women of the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion in England. In the middle is Major Charity Adams. She&#x27;s inspecting the women under her command." caption="Women of the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion in England. In the middle is Major Charity Adams. She&#x27;s inspecting the women under her command." loading="lazy" width="3000" height="2324" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 200px)" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcpdb6888th02.7b19c2ee.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><figcaption align="center"><b>Somewhere in England, Maj. Charity E. Adams, Columbia, S.C., and Capt. Abbie N. Campbell, Tuskegee Institute, Tuskegee, Ala, during an inspection in February 1945. (Courtesy of NARA: NAID: 531249)</b></figcaption>
The 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion holds a unique place in American military history as the only all-Black, all-female unit deployed during World War II. The battalion was comprised of 855 women, many of whom were members of the Women’s Army Corps (WAC). They faced not only the challenges of military service but also the pervasive racism and sexism of the era. Their primary mission was to sort and deliver mail, which was backlogged due to the war. The unit was stationed in Birmingham, England, where they quickly went to work, processing over 17 million pieces of mail during their deployment.</p>
<h2 id="major-charity-adams">Major Charity Adams</h2>
<p>One of the most remarkable aspects of the 6888th’s history is the leadership of Major Charity Adams, the first Black woman to command a battalion in the Women&#x27;s Army Corps. Adams and her fellow soldiers overcame significant obstacles, including inadequate facilities and discrimination, to fulfill their mission with exceptional dedication. They famously operated under the motto: “No mail, no morale,” recognizing that communication from loved ones was vital to the spirits of the soldiers overseas.</p>
<h2 id="service-across-the-sea">Service across the sea</h2>
<p>Their efforts were met with considerable praise, and they became known as the &quot;Six Triple Eight.&quot; The battalion’s work not only improved the morale of the troops but also set a precedent for future generations of women in the military.<br/>
In addition to their service, it was also an opportunity for these women to travel and see sights they’d never see otherwise. As Indiana Hunt Martin of the 6888th recounted in an interview: “Me and another girl friend of mine, I think it was Christen. We’d just get on a bus and ride it to the end and then ride it back. In France and in England. We’d ride a bus to the end and then wait until the bus would turn around and get on and come back.”</p>
<h2 id="soon-on-netflix">Soon on Netflix</h2>
<p>Despite their significant contributions, the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion remained largely unrecognized for decades. It wasn’t until the 21st century that their story began to receive the acknowledgment it deserves. In 2019, the unit was awarded the Congressional Gold Medal, a testament to their service and sacrifice. On 6 December 2024 a movie dedicated to the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion will be released and on 20 December the movie will premier on Netflix.</p>
<h2 id="legacy-of-the-6888th-central-postal-directory-battalion">Legacy of the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion</h2>
<p>Today, the legacy of the 6888th continues to inspire. Their determination and resilience serve as a powerful reminder of the vital roles that women of color have played in shaping military history. As we commemorate their contributions, let us ensure that their stories are preserved and celebrated for future generations.<br/>
Want to help me with my research? Check out my <a href="https://www.patreon.com/samueldekorte">Patreon</a>. As a thank you, you’ll get a monthly postcard featuring Black American soldiers during the Second World War.   Check out my <a href="https://samueldekorte-shop.fourthwall.com/">webshop</a>, where I’ve made a collection of items dedicated to the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion. The profits are used for researching Black American soldiers during the Second World War.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Photograph 578th Field Artillery Battalion!]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/photograph-578th-field-artillery-battalion</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/photograph-578th-field-artillery-battalion</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Recently I bought a photograph of the 578th Field Artillery Battalion.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently I have set up a Patreon and I use this money for historical research. Part of this research is the acquisition of items, which I then share with you. An example is the image below, of the 578th Field Artillery Battalion. I have shared this image with my patreons first, before sharing it here.</p>
<img alt="An 8-inch howitzer of the 578th Field Artillery Battalion. The gun is in the middle of the photograph, while standing around it are Black American soldiers." loading="lazy" width="11821" height="9326" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px)" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F578thfagunjpg.ec8b4d00.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>A shell is being loaded into an 8-inch howitzer of the 578th Field Artillery Battalion (Bleialf, Germany, 9 February 1945). (Author collection)</em></p>
<h2 id="578th-field-artillery-battalion">578th Field Artillery Battalion</h2>
<p>The 578th Field Artillery Battalion was a segregated unit of the United States Army that served during World War II. Equipped with 8-inch guns, this battalion provided heavy artillery support for Allied forces during key operations in the European Theater. They were one of the two Black American heavy artillery battalions. The other battalion was the 999th Field Artillery Battalion.</p>
<p>Constituted in 1942, the 578th Field Artillery Battalion underwent training and preparation in the United States before deploying to France late in June 1944. As a heavy artillery unit, the 578th Field Artillery Battalion was employed as a corps artillery unit and provided long-range fire support for infantry and armored units advancing across France, Belgium and later Germany. The 8-inch guns they operated were capable of delivering powerful, accurate fire against enemy fortifications, troop concentrations, and other strategic targets. The heavy artillery battalions generally had six guns per battalion. Heavy artillery units like the 578th were often used to soften enemy defenses before major offensives and to disrupt enemy movements and supply lines.</p>
<h2 id="obliteration-was-the-result">Obliteration was the Result</h2>
<p>As Master Sergeant Floyd Jones, who served in the 578th Field Artillery Battalion, explained their guns: “Now, you understand we could spread fire; so many guns on several different targets. In short, we could batter the hell out of a number of targets at once or we could zero in on one. With all that firepower on one objective, obliteration was the result.” (Mary Motley Pennick, The Invisible Soldier, Detroit 1975, 181.)</p>
<p>The 578th Field Artillery Battalion performed their service valiantly during the Second World War. They contributed to the overall Allied victory in Europe and helped free the people in Europe of the joke of Nazism.</p>
<p>Want to view the image in the gallery? Click <a href="/images">here</a>.</p>
<p>Want to help my research? Check out my Patreon <a href="https://www.patreon.com/samueldekorte/about?l=en">here</a>. As a thank you, you&#x27;ll receive a monthly postcard featuring Black American soldiers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Just an image of the 218th Quartermaster Battalion]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/218th-quartermaster-battalion</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/218th-quartermaster-battalion</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I am currently on a writing retreat in Italy and I’m focused on my project about the 777th Field Artillery Battalion. In between working on that project, I thought I’d take a small moment to share something with you.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m currently on a writing retreat in Italy and I’m focused on my project about the 777th Field Artillery Battalion. In between working on that project, I thought I’d take a small moment to share something with you.</p>
<h2 id="just-a-photograph">Just a Photograph</h2>
<p>Let me show a photograph. It&#x27;s an image from the Second World War. Look closely and take a moment to consider what you see.</p>
<img alt="Black American soldiers are fueling jerricans." caption="Black American soldiers are fueling jerricans." loading="lazy" width="2846" height="2266" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 200px)" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F218qmbn.7ed4e845.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<figcaption align="center"><b>(Courtesy of United States Heritage and Education Center)</b></figcaption>
<p>On the reverse of the photograph is written: “Huge tank truck discharge their cargo of gasoline into ‘jerricans’ lined up along the road at the 218th Quartermaster Battalion dump in Germany. This gas dump supplies fuel to the U.S. Ninth Army. 3/23/45. Wegberg, Germany.”</p>
<p>At first glance, it seems that it’s “just” another quartermaster battalion providing fuel for the advancing Allied armies. However, there’s a lot more going on here than you might think. Now, I’m guessing most of you have never heard of the 218th Quartermaster Battalion and that’s also fine. It was one of the many quartermaster units in the army at that time.</p>
<p>Likewise, “Ninth Army”, the location “Wegberg, Germany” and the date 23 March 1945, don’t mean much separate of each other. But when you think about it, this was right before Operation Flashpoint was launched. The advance of the US Ninth Army across the Rhine River, which plunged deeper into Germany and eventually sealed the Ruhr pocket.</p>
<img alt="A map showing the advance of the US Ninth Army during Operation Flashpoint." caption="The advance of the US Ninth Army during Operation Flashpoint." loading="lazy" width="1515" height="1005" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 200px)" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmcr.b0cc6091.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<figcaption align="center"><b>The advance of the US Ninth Army during Operation Flashpoint. (Original map is in the public domain)</b></figcaption>
<h2 id="operation-flashpoint">Operation Flashpoint</h2>
<p>Operation Flashpoint was part of the bigger Operation Plunder, which also included an airborne element: Operation Varsity. On 23 March 1945, the British Second Army, the US Ninth Army, and the British 6th Airborne and the American 17th Airborne Divisions, launched an attack together and crossed the Rhine River, which formed the last line of German resistance.</p>
<p>And it&#x27;s due to these facts that this photo is significant. It’s not just text, another numerical designation for a unit, but a glimpse into the historical past. The 218th Quartermaster Battalion literally fueled the advance of the 30th, 35th, 79th Infantry Divisions and the 8th Armored Division! All their vehicles, all their tanks, and also the boats need fuel to operate.</p>
<p>It supplied some 294,000 gallons (1,112,911 liters) of gasoline to the Ninth Army each day. If this battalion hadn’t done its service, then the advance of the army would be stuck. Now, it’s just a small gear in a much bigger machine, but it was there and that’s what matters. This image is direct proof that they were there.</p>
<p>Now, their history is not the stuff of legends and that&#x27;s okay. It’s just to show that there’s a lot more to history and a lot more to the Second World War than you might think. Black American soldiers were part of the United States Army during the Second World War and the work that they did, either at the front or behind it, helped the Allied armies win the war in.</p>
<p>If you’d like to see footage of the 79th Infantry Division crossing the Rhine River, which was in part made possible by the 218th Quartermaster Battalion, check out this video by my friend G.I.stories on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JO3mN7st0UY">YouTube</a>.</p>
<p>Want to help me with my research? Check out my <a href="https://www.patreon.com/samueldekorte">Patreon</a>. As a thank you, you’ll get a monthly postcard featuring Black American soldiers during the Second World War.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honoring First Lieutenant John M. Madison: Officer in the 92nd Infantry Division.]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/honoring-madison</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/honoring-madison</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On the website of the National Archives and Records Administration, there is a section devoted to images of Black Americans during the Second World War. If you scroll down a bit, you’ll see image 235, with the caption: “Brig. Gen. Robert N. Young, Commanding General of the Military District of Washington, assists Melba Rose, aged 2, daughter of Mrs. Rosie L. Madison,...in viewing the Silver Star posthumously awarded her father 1st Lt. John W. Madison, of the 92nd Infantry Division, who was killed in action in Italy...” Immediately, I was curious. What’s the story behind this image?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the website of the National Archives and Records Administration, there is a section devoted to images of <a href="https://www.archives.gov/research/african-americans/ww2-pictures">Black Americans during the Second World War</a>. If you scroll down a bit, you’ll see image 235, with the caption: “Brig. Gen. Robert N. Young, Commanding General of the Military District of Washington, assists Melba Rose, aged 2, daughter of Mrs. Rosie L. Madison,...in viewing the Silver Star posthumously awarded her father 1st Lt. John W. Madison, of the 92nd Infantry Division, who was killed in action in Italy...” Immediately, I was curious. What’s the story behind this image?</p><p><img alt=" Brigade General Robert N. Young, Commanding General of the Military District of Washington, assists Melba Rose, aged 2, daughter of Mrs. Rosie L. Madison,...in viewing the Silver Star posthumously awarded her father 1st Lt. John W. Madison, of the 92nd Infantry Division, who was killed in action in Italy..." loading="lazy" width="3000" height="2419" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-full rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 42rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fmadison2.0797b1a3.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/> * Image from National Archives and Records Administration: NAID: 535559.*</p><h2 id="john-m-madison-and-his-awards">John M. Madison and his awards</h2><p>The photograph shows a Black woman and her daughter, while the white general on the left is holding the medal. It’s a tragic history, because Rosie’s husband and Melba’s father has been killed in combat, while serving with the 92nd Infantry Division. I’ve been digging a bit deeper and located the following newspaper photograph.</p>
<p><img alt="A newspaper clipping featuring the widow and daughter of James M. Madison receiving a medal." loading="lazy" width="524" height="539" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-full rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 42rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FMadison1.e436e263.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/> * Image from The Michigan Chronicle, August 11, 1945.*</p>
<p>The caption even has a typo, because it appears to be John Melvin Madison. His entry on [the American Battle Monuments Commission] (<a href="https://www.abmc.gov/decedent-search/madison%3Djohn">https://www.abmc.gov/decedent-search/madison%3Djohn</a>) also lists him as John M. Madison.</p>
<p>On the website of <a href="https://valor.militarytimes.com/hero/94036">The Hall of Valor Project</a> I found the citation for his Silver Star. It gives some more information on the action for which he was decorated.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>GENERAL ORDERS:</p>
<p>Headquarters, 92d Infantry Division, General Orders No. 15 (April 22, 1945)</p>
<p>CITATION:</p>
<p>The President of the United States of America, authorized by Act of Congress July 9, 1918, takes pride in presenting the Silver Star (Posthumously) to First Lieutenant (Infantry) John Melvin Madison (ASN: 0-331261), United States Army, for gallantry in action while serving with the 370th Infantry Regiment, 92d Infantry Division, in action on 8 and 10 February 1945, in Italy. The company of which First Lieutenant Madison was a member had taken its objective against light enemy resistance. Immediately thereafter, the enemy subjected the position to terrific artillery and mortar fire which killed or wounded all officers except First Lieutenant Madison. Extremely heavy casualties and the loss of leadership disorganized the company and it sought to withdraw. First Lieutenant Madison quickly gathered the remaining fifteen men and, regardless of continuing enemy fire, put them into positions to hold the hill. By sheer personal courage and disregard for his own life, First Lieutenant Madison inspired his men to repel three separate enemy counterattacks aimed exclusively at their position. He withdrew only upon orders. Two days later, he captured seven enemy soldiers while leading his company in an attack routed through an extensive unmarked minefield. First Lieutenant Madison&#x27;s outstanding bravery in a situation of extreme combat hazard exemplifies the gallant heroism of the American Soldier.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>While there’s still a lot to discover about the history of John M. Madison, the sources give more background to the photograph. First Lieutenant Madison served valiantly in combat and died in the service of his country. May he rest in peace.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[May update: A fun surprise]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/source-update-and-wwiidaily</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/source-update-and-wwiidaily</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[History is full of surprises and sometimes these surprises come when you least expect them.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>History is full of surprises and sometimes these surprises come when you least expect them. As some of you might know, every day I post something on Instagram about Black American soldiers during the Second World War. I also collaborate with people and interact with what they post. Recently @worldwarII_daily posted a photograph, which caught my eye. I&#x27;ve added it below. Perhaps you can also spot it.</p>
<img alt="Australian troops storm ashore in the first assault wave to hit Balikpapan on the southeast coast of oil-rich Borneo. Coast Guard Combat Photographer James L. Lonergan stands in the landing craft." loading="lazy" width="3000" height="2386" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound01.64193978.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>(Courtesy of National Archives and Records Administration: NAID: 513227)</em></p>
<p>If not, once you zoom in, you can see that the hands that the hands of the man wearing the life preserver are a different color than those of the surrounding people. He&#x27;s the man in the red circle. I was intruiged and dug a bit deeper, where I found another photograph. It’s mostlikely made by James L. Lonergan, who is seen standing up with the camera in the first photograph. He&#x27;s the man in the yellow circle.</p>
<img alt="Australian troops storm ashore in the first assault wave to hit Balikpapan on the southeast coast of oil-rich Borneo. Coast Guard Combat Photographer James L. Lonergan stands in the landing craft." loading="lazy" width="2293" height="1822" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound02.5143a4e7.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>(Courtesy of National Archives and Records Administration: NAID: 513227)</em></p>
<p>As you can see in the images below, the Coast Guardsman is a Black American.</p>
<img alt="Coast Guardsmen Land Aussies in Balikpapan Invasion." loading="lazy" width="1746" height="1696" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound03.bb95c5a0.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>(Courtesy of National Archives and Records Administration: NAID: 205584118)</em></p>
<p>This is the original image that James L. Lonergan took, which you can see in the first photograph.</p>
<img alt="Coast Guardsmen Land Aussies in Balikpapan Invasion." loading="lazy" width="5628" height="4744" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffound04.7fef6229.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>(Courtesy of National Archives and Records Administration: NAID: 205584118)</em></p>
<p>Whereas the discovery of this image doesn’t alter the perception of history, it’s once more a confirmation that Black Americans were there and the contribution of Black Americans during the Second World War.</p>
<p>Interested in more from World War II Daily Postcast? You can find it <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4DOxOOi0S3cxcMjms6Mq0M?si=6cYrANmoT4CXBsGrNGOAOA">here</a>.<br/>
Interested in what @worldwarII_daily posts on Instagram? You can find it <a href="https://www.instagram.com/worldwarii_daily?igsh=b2hxbzh1Z2lsaWox">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="update-8-may">Update 8 May</h2>
<p>Another source has been added! It&#x27;s the book <em>Come Out Fighting: The Epic Tale of the 761st Tank Battalion</em>. It&#x27;s written by Trezzvant Anderson, a journalist who covered the battalion, and published in 1945. The book is full of stories and photographs. Feel free to check it out <a href="/sources">here</a>!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Patreon update]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/patreon-update</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/patreon-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Currently, there is a gap in the existing historiography. Black American soldiers are systematically ignored, forgotten, or tokenized. To acknowledge and address the contributions of these brave warriors, it is important to share the history of Black American soldiers during the Second World War.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="#executive-summary">Executive summary</a></li>
<li><a href="#who-is-samuel-de-korte">Who is Samuel de Korte?</a></li>
<li><a href="#why-does-this-matter">Why does this matter?</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-is-the-money-used-for">What is the money used for?</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-are-the-benefits-of-supporting-this-research">What are the benefits of supporting this research?</a></li>
<li><a href="#why-do-you-mail-postcards">Why do you mail postcards?</a></li>
<li><a href="#appendix-1-samuel-de-korte">Appendix 1: Samuel de Korte</a></li>
<li><a href="#appendix-2-the-costs-of-doing-research">Appendix 2: The costs of doing research</a></li>
<li><a href="#appendix-3-examples-of-postcards">Appendix 3: Examples of postcards</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="executive-summary">Executive summary</h2>
<p>Currently, there is a gap in the existing historiography. Black American soldiers are systematically ignored, forgotten, or tokenized. To acknowledge and address the contributions of these brave warriors, it is important to share the history of Black American soldiers during the Second World War. To do so costs time and money. You can help change changing this, for as little as $ 5.00 per month. With your support from a monthly contribution of $ 10.00 or more, you’ll be mailed every month a postcard featuring Black American soldiers during the Second World War, while also funding the research that I am doing. To donate on Patreon, click <a href="https://www.patreon.com/samueldekorte">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="who-is-samuel-de-korte">Who is Samuel de Korte?</h2>
<p>I&#x27;ve studied ‘Contemporary History of Modern Europe’ at Utrecht University in the Netherlands and wrote my MA thesis about the representation of Black American soldiers during the Second World War. Black American soldiers are underrepresented in contemporary history and I kept thinking about this fact. I want to help solve this problem.<br/>
After having finished my studies, I made it my mission to raise awareness for Black American soldiers during the Second World War. They suffered from discrimination during enlistment, during their service, or afterward when they returned to civilian life. However, many Black soldiers, when presented with the opportunity, performed valiantly.<br/>
I raise awareness for their contribution by writing about Black American units during World War Two, so that their efforts are not forgotten. Past projects include a book about the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion (Finalist, 2022 Army Historical Foundation Distinguished Writing Awards), while upcoming projects include a book about the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion and a book about the 777th Field Artillery Battalion.<br/>
Digitized images, which are part of the research, have been made available online, such as photographs of the 76th Coast Artillery Regiment. Additional research discovered the unit history of the 969th Field Artillery Battalion, titled the Golden Cannon, which can be downloaded for free on my website and is thus publicly available or finding film footage of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion. He also discovered a photograph of Mack B. Anderson, thus providing a face to a true American hero. See <a href="#appendix-1-samuel-de-korte">Appendix 1</a> for more information about me and my social media presence.</p>
<h2 id="why-does-this-matter">Why does this matter?</h2>
<p>Black American soldiers are often ignored or left out of the history of the Second World War, even though at that time around 10% of the US Army consisted of Black American soldiers. This is a serious problem because we cannot overcome historical injustices until we identify and address them. In part, this also contributes to problems experienced in US society today. There’s talk about history, but Black and white history is not the same. Even though Black and white soldiers served in the same war, they had vastly different experiences. By learning about their different experiences and different perspectives on the war, we can better understand the problems of the present. By raising awareness for all Black American units and their efforts during the war, we’re addressing that issue one postcard at a time.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-the-money-used-for">What is the money used for?</h2>
<p>The money is used to fund the research. This research consists of several components, time to do research and write, as well as money to do research. Sometimes historical images need to be digitized so that they can be made publicly available or archival documents need to be digitized to gain access to them. All of this costs money, which is where you can help. The income of the project will thus be used to fund further research as well as make time available to do this research. See <a href="#appendix-2-the-costs-of-doing-research">Appendix 2</a> for some of the costs of research. If you wish to make a one-time or a monthly donation, click <a href="https://www.patreon.com/samueldekorte">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-the-benefits-of-supporting-this-research">What are the benefits of supporting this research?</h2>
<p>History is about sharing and I believe that I should make as much of the history available for free as possible. That’s why I uploaded the images of the 76th Coastal Artillery Regiment or shared the unit history of the 969th Field Artillery Battalion. I don’t like paywalls. The end goal should always be to make as much available for free as possible.<br/>
By having an additional stream of revenue, I can spend more time researching and writing and being less reliant on my day job to fund the research. This allows everyone involved to raise awareness for Black American soldiers during the Second World War, which will lead to a better understanding of our historical differences and actively help create a better world.</p>
<h2 id="why-do-you-mail-postcards">Why do you mail postcards?</h2>
<p>It’s an extra boost to raise awareness for the contribution of Black American soldiers during the Second World War. It’s done to thank the people who donate monthly $ 10.00 or more. They make it possible for me to do research and I want to share interesting images with them. Thus they receive a postcard every month featuring a reprinted photograph of Black American soldiers during the Second World War, while on the back of the postcard is a short explanation of the image featured on the other side. This will be sent to their home or the address that they provide. (Unless people wish to opt out.) See <a href="#appendix-3-examples-of-postcards">Appendix 3</a> for two examples.</p>
<h2 id="appendix-1-samuel-de-korte">Appendix 1: Samuel de Korte</h2>
<p>Social media presence:<br/>
<a href="www.samueldekorte.com">Website</a><br/>
<a href="https://www.instagram.com/samuel.dekorte/">Instagram</a><br/>
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/samuel.dekorte">Facebook</a><br/>
<a href="https://www.threads.net/@samuel.dekorte">Threads</a><br/>
<a href="https://www.patreon.com/samueldekorte">Patreon</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.samueldekorte.com/books">Books</a><br/>
Of special importance are the following two books:<br/>
The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion: Fighting on Both Fronts (2022)
Black American soldiers are consistently ignored or forgotten, while they did participate in the Second World War. Based upon archival material, other sources, and conversations with descendants, I wrote a book about one of the segregated American units.
<a href="https://www.pen-and-sword.co.uk/The-614th-Tank-Destroyer-Battalion-Hardback/p/20573">Link to the publisher</a>.</p>
<p>Tuskegee Airmen: Dogfighting with the Luftwaffe and Jim Crow (2024)
During the Second World War, the Tuskegee Airmen had not one but two enemies to overcome: the German Luftwaffe and Jim Crow. In this book, the inspiring history of these men is recounted detailing the struggles the men faced at home and abroad.
<a href="https://www.pen-and-sword.co.uk/Tuskegee-Airmen-Hardback/p/24428">Link to the publisher</a>.</p>
<p>Additionally, in 2025 a book on the history of the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery will appear.</p>
<p>Articles:<br/>
Black Soldiers, the Second World War, and Historical Comic books: An Examination of Black American Soldiers in Comic Books about the Second World War, The Hellfighter, 2023
An examination of Black American soldiers in comic books. Two separate comic books are analyzed regarding their portrayal of Black American soldiers, their service, and their impact during the Second World War. This is then contrasted with their actual participation in order to gain a better understanding of the blind spots in contemporary popular culture. In this case, the comic books focus on action and exciting elements, forgoes the more complicated topics in American history, such as segregation and racism.</p>
<h2 id="appendix-2-the-costs-of-doing-research">Appendix 2: The costs of doing research</h2>
<p><a href="https://ahec.armywarcollege.edu/documents/FeeforServiceSchedule.pdf">USAHEC</a></p>
<ol>
<li>Fee for digitized photograph at given dpi $20.00</li>
<li>Fee for non-digitized photograph at 300 dpi $20.00</li>
<li>Fee for non-digitized photograph at 600 dpi $35.00</li>
<li>Fee for non-digitized oversize items at 600dpi $45.00</li>
<li>Fee for non-digitized photograph at 1200dpi $50.00
REQUEST FOR REPRODUCTION OF PRINTED MATERIAL</li>
<li>Non-Digitized Material for Offsite Patrons
a) Fee for photocopy reproduction:
•	1 - 5 pages $5.00
•	6 – 12 pages $10.00
•	13 – 23 pages $20.00
•	24 and over pages $0.80 per page
•	Oversized material is $1.50 per image
b) Fee for 300 dpi scan reproduction:
•	1 to 10 pages $10.00
•	11 to 20 pages $20.00
•	21 to 30 pages $30.00
•	Over 30 pages $1.00 per page
•	Oversized material is $2.00 per image</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://www.archives.gov/research/order/fees">The National Archives and Records Administration</a><br/>
NARA Reproduction Services (minimum reproduction order fees may apply)
Paper to paper (up to and including 11” x 17”)			 $0.80 per copy</p>
<p>NARA Reproduction Services (minimum reproduction order fees may apply)
Paper to paper (up to and including 11” x 17”)			 $0.80 per copy</p>
<p>Archival Handling Fees								               Fee
Motion Picture/Video Item (Washington, DC) 				   $17.25 per item</p>
<p><a href="https://dh.howard.edu/MSRC_Fees_and_Permissions2024.pdf">Howard University</a><br/>
Social Media (Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, etc.)
Commercial Organization (Non-promotional) 					$175
E-book or Audiobook with worldwide rights 					$950</p>
<h2 id="appendix-3-examples-of-postcards">Appendix 3: Examples of postcards</h2>
<p>The front and back of a postcard featuring the 593rd Field Artillery Battalion.</p>
<img alt="The front of a postcard featuring Black American soldiers of the 593rd Field Artillery Battalion." loading="lazy" width="5615" height="4366" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex01.98a52c16.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<img alt="The back of a postcard." loading="lazy" width="617" height="873" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex01.4c39ddd8.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p>The front and back of a postcard featuring an armorer of the 332nd Fighter Group.</p>
<img alt="The front of a postcard featuring an armorer of the 332nd Fighter Group." loading="lazy" width="2953" height="1988" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffex02.431709a1.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<img alt="The back of a postcard." loading="lazy" width="617" height="873" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbex02.58072c30.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Short documentaries for the Militology Channel]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/militology-channel</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/militology-channel</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[For the Militology channel on Youtube I write scripts about a variety of topics. One of the scripts, which I have written, is about the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="militology">Militology</h2>
<p>For the Militology channel on Youtube I write scripts about a variety of topics. One of the scripts, which I have written, is about the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion. I&#x27;m proud of it and I wanted to share it with you.</p>
<h2 id="the-militology-channel">The Militology Channel</h2>
<p>The Militology channel is dedicated to military history and explores past battles, weapons, tactics, generals and heroes throughout history. Among others, I&#x27;ve also written a script about <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SwyDvTeb2qY">Doris Miller</a> and another one about the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CYBgbwqPDTA">Tuskegee Airmen</a>.</p>
<h2 id="watch-it-online">Watch it online!</h2>
<p>The whole documentary is online and can be watched on Youtube!</p>
<div class="aspect-video w-full overflow-hidden rounded-md"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yUw5823D-vM" class="h-full w-full" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<p>If the clip doesn&#x27;t show, you can also watch it <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yUw5823D-vM">here</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[April updates: sources added]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/april-update</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/april-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[As a historian, I truly believe that history should be freely accessible. During my research about Black American soldiers during the Second World War, I came across various sources, which I had digitized and are now publicly available.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a historian, I truly believe that history should be freely accessible. During my research about Black American soldiers during the Second World War, I came across various sources, which I had digitized and are now publicly available. The same goes for photographs, which I had digitized as part of my research, and which are now also available on my website. One of the things I&#x27;ve made available is the book <em>The Golden Cannon: A history of the 969th Field Artillery Battalion</em>. Feel free to check it out <a href="/sources">here</a>!</p><h2 id="update-18-april">Update 18 April</h2><p>I&#x27;ve also uploaded several images of the 76th Coast Artillery Regiment, which can be viewed <a href="/images">here</a>, and included a letter from their chaplain, Luther M. Fuller, where he remarked on his service with the regiment and their hopes for the future.</p>
<p><img alt="An image of Luther M. Fuller, clipped from an online newspaper." loading="lazy" width="313" height="556" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-full rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 42rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ffuller01.dbbe87b4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/> <em>Luther M. Fuller. (The Guardian, 22 August 1942)</em></p>
<p><strong>Published in <em>The Guardian</em>, August 22, 1942.</strong><br/>
<strong>THE SPIRIT OF THE 76th COAST ARTILLERY (AA)</strong><br/>
<em>By Chap. Luther M. Fuller</em><br/>
<em>SAN FRANCISCO, CAL—Well Folks, here we are writing to you away out in Cool San Francisco, California, where it is common to see women wearing their fur coats in the month of August. This time we are writing, not about the 372nd Infantry of which we have been writing so long, but about a New Regiment, the 76th Coast Artillery Anti Aircraft which is two years old in this month, having been activated at Ft. Bragg, N. C., in August 1940. It is an all-Colored Regiment officered by white personnel, except the two Chaplains. We joined this Regimental after an eleven day journey from New York City through states in the deep south like the Hot Desert Sands of Utah, Arizona, and Nevada. On our way, we visited Denver, Colorado, Omaha, Nebraska, Chicago, Illinois, Salt Lake City, Uth and many other historic places.</em></p>
<p><em>The Spirit of the 76th Coast Artillery is one of Freedom and Democracy. Here we have no discrimination or segregation. The white Commissioned Officers and the Colored Chaplains eat in the same Mess Hall, at the same tables reserved for Officers, sleep in the same barracks, and use the same Shower Baths and washroom. Doesn’t it seem strange that white officers from states in the deep south like Mississippi, South and North Carolina, Georgia, and Tennessee should be sharing these privileges with Colored Officers? But it is a real fact, &quot;believe it or not.” Of course, some of them may not like it but there is nothing they can do about it but to take it and like it. Our Commanding Officer is a native of California and will not tolerate any prejudice and discrimination in the 76th Coast Artillery.</em></p>
<p><em>I say that the Spirit of the 76th is one of Freedom, Yea, one of Freedom from the weights and shackles of race prejudice, discrimination, and damnable segregation at home and from dictatorship and slavery abroad. The men of our Regiment are anxious to go abroad to fight for Freedom and Democracy, Yea for Christian Democracy, they are not unmindful of the lack of Freedom at home. They are greatly imbued with the same Spirit of Freedom which gripped the hearts of the Revolutionary Patriots of 1776. The same spirit which caused Patrick Henry to say: &quot;Give me Liberty or give me death!” They are well aware of the fact that they, more than any other race, have more to gain by a victory over the Axis Nations. For them, it will be victory over injustice, inequality race prejudice, segregation, and discrimination at home as well as a victory for Christian Democracy abroad.</em></p>
<p><em>The Spirit of the 76th Coast Artillery is one of Christianity. There are more real Christians in this regiment than we have found in any others with which we have come in contact. Practically in every Battery there u a Chorus or a Quartette and all delight in singing the songs of Zion and the deep and emotional Spirituals of the Colored Race. The continued cursing and swearing so prevalent in other regiments is conspicuously lacking in the 76th Coast Artillery. At our morning service last Sunday more than thirty soldiers came forward and gave their lives for Christ. It was a rare spectacle to behold in the Army. Real talent in our Regiment is plentiful. We have musicians, school teachers College men, poets, newspaper men, and writers in great numbers. The level of intelligence is very high. So, again we say, that the Spirit of the 76th Coast Artillery is one of real freedom, real liberty and real Christian Democracy.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allied air assaults in the movie Jugend by Alessandro Pepe]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/allied-air-assaults</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/allied-air-assaults</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In the movie Jugend by filmmaker Alessandro Pepe about the SS-division Hitlerjugend the relationship with a SS soldier and his girlfriend at home is examined. The twist at the end of the film is -spoiler alert- that his girlfriend has already died in an Allied bombardment. In this article we will examine the mentioned numbers to see if these are correct and what the consequences of this are.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>[This article appeared previously in Dutch <a href="https://www.historien.nl/geallieerde-luchtaanvallen-in-film-jugend-van-van-alessandro-pepe/">here</a>. It has been translated and adapted into the current form.]</em></p>
<p>In the movie Jugend by filmmaker Alessandro Pepe about a soldier in the Waffen-SS division <em>Hitlerjugend</em> the relationship with a SS soldier and his girlfriend at home is examined. The twist at the end of the film is -<em>spoiler alert</em>- that his girlfriend has already died in an Allied bombardment. In this article we will examine the mentioned numbers to see if these are correct and what the consequences of this are.</p>
<h2 id="france-1944">France 1944</h2>
<p>In the slightly less than twenty minutes movie a young SS soldier is introduced as the main character. He is in France in 1944 after the Allied armies had landed in Normandy and he regularly writes to his beloved in Germany. He notices that she has not answered his most recent letters and this frustrates him. At the end of the movie, after the death of the main character, it turns out that his girlfriend didn’t write to him because she was killed two months previously in an allied bombardment.<br/>
At the end of the movie two remarkable claims are made to put the movie in a certain perspective.  “Indoctrinated since young ages, some of these boys were pushed to commit war crimes,” and “more than 550,000 German civilians died after bombs.” Another article would be needed to clarify the mistakes in the first comment, about the simplifications in it, and about absolving guilt. This article will focus on the second quote because the context is important in which it is made.</p>
<h2 id="suffering-of-german-soldiers">Suffering of German soldiers</h2>
<p>In the movie, the girlfriend is shown as an example of the suffering of German soldiers and their families, because she has passed away earlier and the main character never found out what happened to her. The audience is supposed to feel pity for the German civilians who were the victims of these bombardments. Yet certain things are just not right and certain remarks need to be made to put the film in the right context.</p>
<h2 id="wrong-numbers">Wrong numbers</h2>
<p>It’s indeed true that the Allied air forces bombed many times over Germany and the occupied territories. These bombardments were not always precise and there were many casualties, including elderly, children, and babies. Not only Germans, but also people that worked (voluntarily or involuntarily) in Germany, were threatened by these attacks. For every single ton of bombs that the Germans had used on the United Kingdom, there were 315 tons of bombs thrown at Germany. These are remarkable numbers and it&#x27;s indeed good that attention is drawn to this.<br/>
However, the problem with the movie is not that it mentions these numbers. According to the movie, there were 550.000 Germans killed. Research gives different numbers. Richard Overy, claimed in 2015 that there were 353,000 Germans killed as a result of the bombings. In the books by the East German historian Olaf Groehler, between 360,000 and 370,000 Germans fell victim to the bombs. Other numbers talk about 410,000 dead. The only one that remotely comes close is a report by the German Red Cross, which mentions 500,000 victims.</p>
<img alt="Boeing B-17 Flying Fortress over Osnabruck, Germany. Blind bombing is necessary due to the thick clouds over the target. The bomber is of the 91st Bomb Group." loading="lazy" width="3441" height="2872" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fusbomber.89598c0e.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>A B-17 Flying Fortress bomber of the 91st Bomber Group over Osnabruck, Germany. (Courtesy of NARA: NAID: 204898733)</em></p>
<h2 id="dresden">Dresden</h2>
<p>The discussion about victims and people killed is difficult. Take the bombing of Dresden as an example, where there were between 25,000 and 60,000 casualties. Understandably it is difficult to determine the exact number of fatalities, especially when even a single attack has an error margin of 35,000 casualties. However, that doesn’t mean that the number of 550,000 is absurdly high. Where these numbers come from and what considerations Pepe made before he decided to mention this number is not clarified. A source could have prevented a lot of discussions, but the discussion about the exact numbers of casualties is not deemed important to this movie and instead, a too high number of German casualties is just given.</p>
<h2 id="cities-targeted-by-bombardments">Cities targeted by bombardments</h2>
<p>To discuss the bombings of cities during the Second World War a certain perspective needs to be given. The first bombardment of the Second World War was on the Polish town of Wielun, where there were 127 casualties. In the Netherlands the bombing of Rotterdam is infamous and one can still see the traces of this bombardment in the city center. There were between 650 and 900 people killed.<br/>
In the Third Reich, there was even an euphemism to refer to the destruction of cities, ‘coventrieren’, named after the bombardment of the English town Coventry. It’s saying a lot that there existed a term to refer to the ruining of cities. Also, the Allied forces conducted bombardments on cities, where the bombing of Dresden, where there were a lot of casualties shortly before the end of the war, or the dropping of atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki, which forced an end to the Second World War. There were around 199,000 casualties.</p>
<img alt="A photograph of the Polish city Wielun after the German bombardment during the Second World War." loading="lazy" width="1500" height="1003" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwielun.b3b32dc4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>The devestation in the city Wielun after the German bombardment.</em></p>
<h2 id="germany-as-the-victim">Germany as the victim</h2>
<p>By leaving out these facts and just focusing on one aspect, a one-sided view is given. Germany is presented more as a victim of the Second World War instead of the aggressor. The numbers are enlarged and the past is treated unjustly. Pepe tries to give an interesting perspective of the Second World War, but the only thing he does is help Second World War revisionists.</p>
<h2 id="das-boot">Das Boot</h2>
<p>A film that gives a good perspective of one aspect of the Second World War is the German movie Das Boot. The battle takes place under the sea instead of in the air. Attention is given not just to moments of tension when there is danger or the titular boat is under attack, but also to how the men are forced to cooperate with each other in confined spaces and always be in each other&#x27;s proximity.</p>
<h2 id="reproduction-uniforms">Reproduction uniforms</h2>
<p>The concerning aspect is that Pepe in the making of this movie has been helped by Progetto900, a historical organization. Their goal is to take history out of the museums and they do this by wearing reproduction uniforms with partially authentic equipment. Remarkable is that they inform the reader on their website that they reject the nazi worldview, but they do cooperate with films that Pepe has made. Respect for the past doesn’t Pepe seem to have, because he carries out a pretend-idealistic projection of the past or potentially to quickly earn money with a barely disguised revisionist movie. The choice to depict a German army soldier in the movie would be a lot less controversial than deciding to reenact an SS soldier. As such, by cooperating with making this movie Progetto900 inadvertently aids in furthering the goals of a worldview, which they claim to reject on their website.</p>
<h2 id="less-positive-aspects-of-the-allied-campaigns">Less positive aspects of the Allied campaigns</h2>
<p>While it is good to devote attention to the Second World War in all its forms and features, including the less positive sides of the Allied soldiers, it is important to remember the context of the Second World War. This context makes certain aspects stand out, but also reminds us that one party systematically exterminated people based upon their beliefs, race, sexual or political preference.
The film would have been better if it mentioned how many forced laborers died due to the bombing or how many French civilians died during the Allied bombings in Normandy in preparation for the landings. Another aspect would be to discuss the bombing of Nijmegen, a city in the Netherlands, on 22 February 1944. Instead, it seems that Pepe seemed eager to produce a film about nazis as people we should pity because they suffer from the evil allied air forces.</p>
<h2 id="sources">Sources:</h2>
<p>NIOD, <em>Duitse en geallieerde bombardementen op Nederland (cijfers),</em> <a href="https://www.niod.nl/nl/vraag-en-antwoord/duitse-en-geallieerde-bombardementen-op-nederland">link</a><br/>
The Avalon Project, <em>The Atomic Bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, Chapter 10 - Total Casualties,</em> <a href="http://avalon.law.yale.edu/20th_century/mp10.asp">link</a><br/>
Modris Ekstein, <em>Rites of Spring,</em> page 302.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Honor was Loyalty: SS-romanticization in contemporary media]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/my-honor-was-loyalty</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/my-honor-was-loyalty</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In various media, a skewed perception of the SS is given. This twisted projection of the past can have different consequences, which again influence other media. But where does this representation come from and what is the role of historians in this process?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>[This article appeared previously in Dutch <a href="https://www.historien.nl/kurowski/">here</a>. It’s been translated and adapted into the current form. Netflix also removed the film My Honor was Loyalty in March 2021.]</em></p>
<p>In various media, a skewed perception of the SS is given. This twisted projection of the past can have different consequences, which again influence other media. But where does this representation come from and what is the role of historians in this process?</p>
<h2 id="my-honor-was-loyalty">My Honor was Loyalty</h2>
<p>The film My Honor Was Loyalty (2016) by Alessandro Pepe is made accessible to a large audience by making it available on Netflix. Netflix is an online streaming service, where people can watch movies or documentaries. The movie deals with a group of SS soldiers of the Leibstandarte-SS Adolf Hitler division, which is different than the German Army, the Wehrmacht. War crimes committed by these SS soldiers are shown but justified as emotional outbursts.<br/>
Soviet soldiers are executed to prevent them from being a threat later. An American prisoner is shot under the pretense of revenge for a killed friend. To make this all even more unbelievable, the main character, an SS sergeant, at a certain moment even helps a Jewish woman. The movie lacks all ideological reflection and the connection between the SS and the nazi worldview is barely established. No moments are spared to ponder on the extermination of the Jewish people or others deemed as subhumans. There is no reflection on the murder of civilians. The large number of war crimes that this Waffen-SS division committed are barely featured at all.</p>
<h2 id="war-crimes">War crimes</h2>
<p>There’s a clear gap between the image of the past that this movie projects and the historical events that have transpired. The SS soldiers were not just soldiers, like those in the German army. The Waffen-SS soldiers were ideologically motivated and they carried out the worldview and ideas of Hitler’s regime. The Leibstandarte-SS Adolf Hitler division was involved in several war crimes. The movie actively tries to excuse, downplay, or ignore it. Besides the bad implications this would have, such as nazi-glorification, it is also a falsification of history.<br/>
However, prohibiting this film from being shown is not the solution to this problem. This ‘creative expression’ has already been created, has received international attention, and has been watched many times. Even if this film is declared forbidden, it’s just a matter of time before another director, potentially out of ignorance, potentially out of other intentions, inappropriately treats this topic.</p>
<img alt="A photograph of two Black American soldiers carrying away a victim of the Malmedy Massacre on a stretcher." loading="lazy" width="2932" height="2315" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fwarcrime01.761069d8.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>Two Black American soldiers carry away a victim of the Malmedy Massacre on a stretcher. The perpretrators inlcuded members of the Leibstandarte Adolf Hitler Division. (Photograph courtesy of the National Archives and Records Administration: NAID: 532956.)</em></p>
<h2 id="franz-kurowski">Franz Kurowski</h2>
<p>The bigger problem is not just a ‘wrong’ director, but a structural problem: public ignorance about skewed perceptions of the Waffen-SS. Several writers are actively pushing for a revisionist view of the Second World War, the SS, and the Holocaust. An example is Franz Kurowski, but several other writers also pursue this goal. Kurowski has written many books during his life, of which a significant part has been devoted to the SS. He wrote down the life story of several men. Take for example his writings about Karl Nicolussi-Leck, in the book Panzer Aces II, which contains several errors and mistakes. Through this, it will be shown that the problem of nazi-glorification is known to academic historians, but not to the larger public.<br/>
The Second World War was a conflict that was fought on a global scale. Enormous losses were sustained by all parties and two nuclear bombs were needed to force an end to the bloodshed. There were millions of casualties and many war crimes were committed by all major parties involved. A special category of victims is those who were murdered based on the despicable ideology of the nazis. In carrying out this ideology the SS, to which Karl Nicolussi-Leck belonged, played a large role. Although Karl Nicolussi-Leck might not have been actively involved in the Holocaust, he was part of an organization that actively carried out the killing of people deemed as subhumans.</p>
<h2 id="karl-nicolussi-leck">Karl Nicolussi-Leck</h2>
<p>Hauptsturmführer Karl Nicolussi-Leck (1917-2008) was a tank commander in the Waffen-SS during the Second World War. He had volunteered for the SS in 1940 and served in the Deutschland, Das Reich, and the Wiking division. In the book, his fighting experiences are stressed, while in the epilogue it’s stressed how he developed an ecological fruit and wine business. Besides that, he helped Germans who were displaced and on his initiative, an empty hospital was converted into two schools and later a museum. During the rebuilding he kept his personal motto, just like in the war; “There’s always plenty to do, let’s get at it!”</p>
<h2 id="positive-characterization">Positive characterization</h2>
<p>A positive image of Karl Nicolussi-Leck is painted. He’s someone that helps others and even cares about the environment. The war was over and he wanted to focus on the future. There’s little negative to remark about him and every ideological reflection is missing. This is striking, because every person has good and bad characteristics and beyond doubt, Nicolussi-Leck must have had some thoughts about his period with the SS.<br/>
Whereas Nicolussi-Leck’s thoughts remain unknown, the writer Franz Kurowski can be faulted for selectively withholding information. After the Second World War, Nicolussi-Leck helped several nazi and SS officers escape to South Africa or the Middle East. In 1948 he went to Argentina but returned after several years. Afterward, he started several businesses with former SS comrades. There’s a clear connection between Nicolussi-Leck’s actions and the nazi worldview, which is lacking in the biography. By not mentioning this, a skewed perception of Nicolussi-Leck is given, as if he was ‘just a soldier’ instead of an ideologically motivated one. To push the argument even further, it’s an attempt by Kurowksi to paint a distorted and positive image of the SS. Kurowski combined these biographies in his book, Panzer Aces II, wherein he shared several experiences of Germans who won the Ritterkreuz.</p>
<img alt="Two German SS soldiers are standing against a wall, while a US soldier guards them." loading="lazy" width="2260" height="2752" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcaptured01.283677a0.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>Sergeant Clarence Mageriea, of the 83rd Division, with two captured German SS troopers against a wall in Sart, Belgium. (Photograph courtesy of the National Archives and Records Administration: NAID: 532956.)</em></p>
<h2 id="ritterkreuz">Ritterkreuz</h2>
<p>The inclusion of the Knight’s Cross (Ritterkreuz) is important, because all men had earned this decoration. However, this medal also had a symbolic value. Between 1939 and 1945 the Ritterkreuz des Eisern Kreuzes handed out just 7,282 times. Recommendations for his award needed to be personally approved by Adolf Hitler. The ideological value is obvious because portrait photos were made of the decorated persons and they gave speeches to other people. The Knight’s Cross holders were supposed to serve as an example. This moralistic approach means that these soldiers were used to spread the nazi worldview. They were thus much more than ‘just’ soldiers.
It is remarkable that in the story of Nicolussi-Leck the ideological aspects of his identity are left behind. The focus is on combat and personal motivations instead of any ideological ideas. Many experiences are viewed from a strictly military perspective. Whereas it’s undeniable that being a soldier was part of the SS experience, they also had a close connection to the nazi paradigm. The Waffen-SS is after the war marked as a criminal organization due to the many war crimes committed during its brief existence.</p>
<h2 id="writers-about-the-waffen-ss">Writers about the Waffen-SS</h2>
<p>The used version of the book Panzer Aces II is published by Stackpole Books, a well-known publisher when it comes to military history. This gives the book Panzer Aces II certain pretensions, such as being historically accurate, which don’t apply to this book. The large volume might also give it a certain value, which makes it more difficult for readers to appropriately judge Kurowski’s work. Thus, the book has an air of legitimacy, which is simply wrong.<br/>
Publishing these distorted histories as if they were authentic biographies, gives fuel to perfidious processes. The book lacks any warning about the author. A mention in the foreword or a warning about the lack of historical accuracy could have prevented a lot of problems. The reader then knows that certain suspicion towards Kurowski is necessary. Although the book might be correct on all technological aspects related to tanks and the German armed forces, it doesn’t mean that the book is also historically accurate. Furthermore, the book contains many little references which are incorrect. The bombing of Dresden is referred to as a terror bombing. Kurowski makes this kind of reference often in his books and is also accused of having a revisionist view of the bombardment. In all Kurowski’s books, he is positive about the German armed forces and often it lacks any nuance.</p>
<h2 id="consequences">Consequences</h2>
<p>In this distorted history lies a task for the historian. Historians need to warn society against this sort of evil powers who use selective history to further their own nefarious goals. With the rise of the ‘alt-right’ movement or other revisionist movements, it is important to remain alert about the published material, because these kinds of books feed such figures.<br/>
People with a history background might know that the books by Kurowski are not entirely trustworthy, but this knowledge needs to be shared with a larger audience. Certain people might not know the difference between the writings of Kurowski and a respected historian and assume both are equally trustworthy while Kurowski’s books are little more than nazi hagiography.</p>
<h2 id="fact-and-fiction">Fact and fiction</h2>
<p>The sad result of these inaccurate books is pathetic films like My Honor was Loyalty by Alessandro Pepe. In this film, intentionally or unintentionally, the SS and its deeds are romanticized. To a large audience, this movie pretends that the SS members are just soldiers and that their crimes can be excused. The line between fact and fiction is not made obvious. Every analysis of the racial ideology of the nazis is missing. Films like this aid nazi worship and the wrongdoings of the nazi regime are pushed into the background, whereas their wrongdoings are things that must never be forgotten.<br/>
Films from the German perspective of the Second World War can be difficult. Due to the Holocaust, there’s an enormous emotional baggage that needs to be taken into account. The German miniseries, Ünsere Mütter, ünsere Väter, makes a good attempt to show several German perspectives of the Second World War.<br/>
It’s impossible to prevent a movie like this and by being available on Netflix, this film will reach a larger audience. However, historians should seize this moment to warn people about the dangers of falsifying history and to raise awareness of the crimes of the nazi regime. As the production of this film shows, not everyone seems to be aware of this, but historians have the possibility to change this. And Pepe should visit the concentration and extermination camps to think about a side of the SS that he has not shown in his movies.</p>
<h2 id="sources">Sources:</h2>
<p>Kurowski, Franz, Panzer Aces II: Battle stories of German tank commanders of WWII (Mechanicsburg 2004).<br/>
Williams, Gordon, Knight’s cross and oak-leaves recipients 1939 – ’40 (Oxford 2012).<br/>
Messenger, David A., &amp; Katrin Paehler (eds.) A Nazi past: Recasting German identity in postwar Europe (Kentucky 2015).<br/>
Kellerhof, Sven Felix, ‘Eine Null anhängen,’ Die Welt (25 January 2005) <a href="https://www.welt.de/print-welt/article371489/Eine-Null-anhaengen.html">https://www.welt.de/print-welt/article371489/Eine-Null-anhaengen.html</a> (28 March 2017)</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[March update: Book appeared and manuscript handed in!]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/march-update</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/march-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It’s been a busy month! Many things have happened and there are two things I wish to highlight for you. First of all, my book on the Tuskegee Airmen appeared. Second, I’ve finished the manuscript of the 452nd Anti-Aircraft artillery Battalion. Read more about them below!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a busy month! Many things have happened and there are two things I wish to highlight for you. First of all, my book on the Tuskegee Airmen appeared. Second, I’ve finished the manuscript of the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion. Read more about it below!</p>
<img alt="The cover of the book Tuskegee Airmen by Samuel de Korte." loading="lazy" width="404" height="600" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>(Photograph courtesy of Pen and Sword Publishers.)</em></p>
<h2 id="tuskegee-airmen-dogfighting-with-the-luftwaffe-and-jim-crow">Tuskegee Airmen: Dogfighting with the Luftwaffe and Jim Crow</h2>
<p>The book about the Tuskegee Airmen has appeared last month! It has been a joy to research these soldiers and to share their history. The Tuskegee Airmen have an interesting history, which includes with the 99th Fighter Squadron, and the 332nd Fighter Group and the 477th Bombardment Group. It’s been a really rewarding project and I’m grateful to Pen and Sword for allowing me to write this book.</p>
<img alt="A photograph of the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion during the Second World War." loading="lazy" width="1024" height="828" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>(Photograph courtesy of the National Archives and Records Administration.)</em></p>
<h2 id="452nd-anti-aircraft-artillery-aaa-battalion-manuscript-handed-in">452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery (AAA) Battalion: Manuscript handed in.</h2>
<p>The other project I finished recently is my upcoming book about the 452nd AAA. It’s been a worthwhile project, because this unit deserves to be more widely known that it currently is. Most of its service in combat was when it was assigned to the XII Corps, Third US Army. The 452nd AAA didn’t fight as a single unit, but assigned platoons to white field artillery battalions. These artillery soldiers were all very glad for their support and more than once, the white soldiers remarked about the skill or dedication of the Black AAA soldiers. Credited with shooting down 67 11/12 enemy aircraft and 19 probables, the 452nd AAA is among the most lethal anti-aircraft battalions of the Second World War. Learn more about their history in my book, once it appears! Currently publication is scheduled for February 2025.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What we can expect from you in 2024?]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/plans-2024</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/plans-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In between all that’s going on, I thought I’d chime in and let you all know what I am working on.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In between all that’s going on, I thought I’d chime in and let you all know what I am working on.</p>
<h2 id="february-deadlines">February deadlines</h2>
<p>As you’ll have noticed, I’m busy with several projects. In February the book about the Tuskegee Airmen appears. Furthermore, in February I need to hand in the manuscript for the book about the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion. After that, there’s a bit of a lull, because once those two projects are wrapped up, things will calm down a bit.</p>
<h2 id="777th-field-artillery-battalion">777th Field Artillery Battalion</h2>
<p>Of course, there are new projects coming up. I’m working on a book about the 777th Field Artillery Battalion. It’s another Black American unit that fought during the Second World War. I have no deadline yet, but once this project gets up and running, I expect things will proceed rapidly.</p>
<p>That’s all for now!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tuskegee Airmen book announced!]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/tuskegee-airmen</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/tuskegee-airmen</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[With pride I can announce that I the book on the Tuskegee Airmen will appear in February 2024! The book deals with the history of the Tuskegee Airmen, which includes the 99th Fighter Squadron, the 332nd Fighter Group as well as the 477th Bombardment Group and the artillery liaison pilots.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With pride I can announce that I the book on the Tuskegee Airmen will appear in February 2024! The book deals with the history of the Tuskegee Airmen, which includes the 99th Fighter Squadron, the 332nd Fighter Group, as well as the 477th Bombardment Group, and the artillery liaison pilots. The main adversary of these pilots was the German Luftwaffe, however, before these Black American pilots could even reach the front, they needed to overcome the prejudices of their white countrymen. However, these men endured the animosity of their fellow countrymen and endured the stresses of combat. They were an essential component in the desegregation of the United States Armed Forces.</p>
<img alt="Cover of the book, titled &#x27;Tuskegee Airmen&#x27; by Samuel de Korte." loading="lazy" width="404" height="600" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px)" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FTuskegee-Airmen.66e702f4.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>Cover of the book &#x27;Tuskegee Airmen&#x27; by Samuel de Korte (Pen and Sword)</em></p>
<h2 id="blurb">Blurb</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>During the Second World War, the Tuskegee Airmen had not one but two enemies to overcome: the German Luftwaffe and Jim Crow. In this book, the inspiring history of these men is recounted detailing the struggles the men faced at home and abroad.</p>
<p>The Tuskegee Airmen were black American pilots who served in the Army Air Corps during the Second World War. However, before earning their wings, these men and women needed to prove themselves to their white countrymen. After all, the racism prevalent at the time meant that black Americans were deemed unsuitable for the demands of modern war.</p>
<p>After completing their training and conducting their first combat missions, the real enemy was waiting for them: the Luftwaffe. As a result of their role escorting the bombers, as well as their bright red tails, the Tuskegee Airmen of 332nd Fighter Group earned the nickname the ‘Red Tails’. The units served with distinction in several fierce engagements, such as the 99th Fighter Squadron, who fought in the skies over Anzio on 27 and 28 January 1944, and the 332nd Fighter Group, who earned a Distinguished Unit Citation for its mission to Berlin on 24 March 1945.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="exciting-project">Exciting Project</h2>
<p>Working on this book has been really exciting and I am grateful that I have been allowed to do so. One of my personal highlights was being invited to the unveiling of a monument dedicated to the 332nd Fighter Group at Ramitelli, the airbase from which this unit operated. I look forward to the publication!</p>
<p>Pre-orders are already available!<br/>
Check out the links below<br/>
<a href="https://www.pen-and-sword.co.uk/Tuskegee-Airmen-Hardback/p/24428">Pen and Sword</a> (UK)<br/>
<a href="https://www.casematepublishers.com/9781399043816/tuskegee-airmen/">Casemate</a> (US)</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Giving a Hero a Face]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/mack-anderson</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/mack-anderson</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[As a historian, you can sometimes be surprised by history. The photograph below is one of such surprises for me, which shows Mack B. Anderson (16 March 1920 – 20 May 1974) of the 823rd Engineer Aviation Battalion. In this article, I will explain why this photograph is so significant.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a historian, you can sometimes be surprised by history. The photograph below is one of such surprises for me, which shows Mack B. Anderson (16 March 1920 – 20 May 1974) of the 823rd Engineer Aviation Battalion. In this article, I will explain why this photograph is so significant.</p>
<img alt="Photograph of Mack B. Anderson of the 823rd Engineer Aviation Battalion. Mack B. Anderson won the Silver Star Award for valor in combat." loading="lazy" width="4602" height="5947" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAnderson.677e7e7c.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>Photograph of Mack B. Anderson of the 823rd Engineer Aviation Battalion. (Public Domain)</em></p>
<h2 id="personal-history">Personal history</h2>
<p>A bit of personal history, but in 2019 I tried to discover more about heroic Black Americans during the Second World War. Accounts of bravery by Black Americans at and behind the frontlines exist and a few stories are widely available, but I wanted to go beyond them. It’s important to note that many Black Americans served in support units and were less likely to experience combat due to their roles. However, danger wasn’t exclusive to the battlefield. Threats could arise unexpectedly, not just from enemy forces but also from hazardous weather or accidents. In Mack B. Anderson’s case, the danger came in the form of bullets fired with hostile intent.</p>
<img alt="Photograph of an Imperial Japanese Zero taking off." loading="lazy" width="605" height="482" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-[3/5] rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fzerofighter.b55646c9.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>An Imperial Japanese zero taking off. (Public Domain)</em></p>
<h2 id="silver-star-medal">Silver Star Medal</h2>
<p>On 25 October 1942, Mack Anderson was stationed at an airfield near Assam when it was attacked by a flight of 18 Japanese Mitsubishi A6M Zero fighter aircraft. While his comrades sought cover, Mack single-handedly manned a .30 machine gun and fired at the fighters. Several times the Zero’s swooped down and strafed Anderson, but he avoided being hit. Eventually, his gun jammed and Anderson ran over to a trench. Once inside the trench, he took out his .45 pistol and continued to fire at the Japanese aircraft. For his heroism, after the attack, he would receive the Silver Star Medal.</p>
<img alt="Newspaper article about Mack B. Anderson of the 823rd Engineer Aviation Battalion. The article explains how Anderson won the Silver Star medal and includes a photograph." loading="lazy" width="284" height="636" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-[4/3] rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800 flex justify-center items-center" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FAndersonarticle.8529a470.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>The newspaper article tells about how Mack B. Anderson earned the Silver Star Medal. (The Southern News, 27 February 1943)</em></p>
<h2 id="transient-glory">Transient Glory</h2>
<p>Now, Mack Anderson’s valor was widely celebrated in the Black American press. The fact that he earned Silver Star, as well as his name and face, were printed in several newspapers throughout the nation. He served as an example. This was caried over into history books, where Anderson is likewise mentioned, such as in The Exclusion of Black Soldiers from the Medal of Honor in World War II, by Elliot V. Converse et al., where on page 154 a short paragraph is dedicated to Anderson. Likewise, in The Employment of Negro Troops by Ulysses Lee also writes about Anderson, although he doesn’t mention him by name when he writes on page 457: ‘From India came the report that though no other Negro units in the theater had been under fire, the conduct of the 823d Engineer Aviation Battalion under hazardous conditions of combat during Japanese raids on Assam in October 1942 was &quot;magnificent.&quot; After the strafing, these engineers returned to their work promptly and began airfield repairs at once. One member of the unit received the Silver Star for action under fire during these raids.’ It’s intriguing that despite these mentions, Anderson’s story has largely been forgotten. For example, in Brenham, Texas, few people seem to be aware of his story.</p>
<img alt="Photographs of various Black American heroes. Some have won the Silver Star medal, but others received other decorations." loading="lazy" width="605" height="749" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fawards.e97f3bed.png&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>Various Black American heroes and the awards they have received. Anderson is mentioned on the right half of the page (Jackson Advocate, 27 November 1943)</em></p>
<h2 id="another-dimension">Another dimension</h2>
<p>While, indeed, Anderson’s story has been preserved in certain books, we can now add a photograph to this story. It adds another dimension to the story, we can add a face to the hero who won the medals. Photographs like this are invaluable. While many photographs exist of battles and movements, this image captures the likeliness of an ‘ordinary’ American who did extraordinary things. It’s a visual representation that is much more appealing to people. It might even inspire some to look up more about the historical context surrounding the image. Lastly, photographs help preserve the memory of a specific event in the past, because images are more effective than remembering events from just words alone. In this case, it’s the history of Mack B. Anderson and how he won the Silver Star Medal for his heroic conduct under fire.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updates about projects: September 2023]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/updates-about-projects</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/updates-about-projects</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The past couple of weeks, I have not been as active as I have been before. I was on holiday in Greece together with some friends. The country was beautiful to visit and we saw many wondrous sights.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The past couple of weeks, I have not been as active as I have been before. I was on holiday in Greece together with some friends. The country was beautiful to visit and we saw many wondrous sights. Now that I’m back and have adjusted to the Dutch climate again, I’m making steady progress with the various projects.</p>
<img alt="Photograph of Members of the Headquarters Company, 480th Port Battalion Set Up Between the Columns of the Ancient Greek Temple of Neptune. Although this location is in Paestum, Sicily, I too have seen many Ancient Greek monuments." loading="lazy" width="460" height="600" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 1000px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Ftemple01.68368d7c.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>Photograph of members of the Headquarters Company, 480th Port Battalion set up between the columns of the Ancient Greek temple of Neptune. Although this location is in Paestum, Sicily, I too have seen many Ancient Greek monuments. (Photograph courtesy of the National Archives and Records Administration.)</em></p>
<h2 id="what-has-happened">What has happened?</h2>
<p>So the translation of C. J. Wagevier’s book, titled <em>Fighting for Napoleon&#x27;s Army in Russia: A POW&#x27;s Memoir</em> has appeared recently. In this book, Wagevier recounts his experiences with the 125th Regiment of the Line, which consisted of Dutch soldiers, during the disastrous Russian Campaign of 1812. It’s been a delight to work on this project! I hope readers have as much joy reading it as I had in translating it.</p>
<h2 id="whats-to-come">What&#x27;s to come?</h2>
<p>Now, there are several projects coming up. I’m still working on the book titled <em>Tuskegee Airmen: Dogfighting with the Luftwaffe and Jim Crow</em>. These Black American pilots fought in the Mediterranean and Europe as part of the 332nd Fighter Group, while the 477th Bombardment Group had to confront Jim Crow at home. It will be published in February 2024. Lastly, I’m making steady progress with the book about the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion. I came across some fascinating sources, which once again reminded me of the joys of historical research.</p>
<p>I will keep you updated!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Busy with projects: Colorizing historical photographs]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/colorizing-images</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/colorizing-images</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Currently, I’m working on a project related to the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion. However, my interest has been captured by something else lately. I’ve been coloring historical images with Artificial Intelligence.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Currently, I’m working on a project related to the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion. However, my interest has been captured by something else lately. I’ve been coloring historical images with Artificial Intelligence.</p>
<h2 id="modern-technology-and-history">Modern technology and history</h2>
<p>Artificial Intelligence has created quite a buzz recently. I’ve been following these developments keenly, not just out of professional interest, but also out of personal curiosity. Artificial Intelligence can be used for a variety of purposes and I’ve been thinking about possibilities for history. One of the uses of AI is to color historical images quickly. These images can then be shared with others to raise awareness or to spark interest.<br/>
Look at the two images below. In it, you will see a half-track of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion together with a few Black American soldiers. First I’ll show you the original image, in black-and-white, and then the same image, but colorized.</p>
<img alt="An image of a half-track of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion. In front of the half-track are two soldiers of the 614th TD Bn." loading="lazy" width="4716" height="4632" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thoriginal.1674edf2.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>(Photograph courtesy of  United States Army Heritage and Education Center.)</em></p>
<img alt="An image of a half-track of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion. In front of the half-track are two soldiers of the 614th TD Bn." loading="lazy" width="1323" height="1300" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614thcolor.4153a00a.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>(Photograph courtesy of  United States Army Heritage and Education Center.)</em></p>
<p>Do you see what a difference it makes?</p>
<h2 id="photographs-come-to-life">Photographs come to life</h2>
<p>Personally, color adds a lot of depth to an image. It’s more interesting and you can appreciate more details that would be harder to spot if the photograph was all in gray tones. Furthermore, it gives you a glimpse of what the past could have been like. It’s no longer an image, but a view of what the past could have been like as the people themselves have experienced it.</p>
<p>Are you also excited about seeing these photographs come to life? I’ve been posting a lot of colorized photographs on my Instagram account. Feel free to check them out &quot;@samuel.dekorte&quot; See you there!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ChatGPT and the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/chatgpt-and-614th-td</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/chatgpt-and-614th-td</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Recently Artificial Intelligence has been a lot in the news and as a Cloud Engineer, I frequently use it to help automate simple tasks in my work. Of course, I was also curious about the other options and thus I decided to ask it to teach me about the ‘614th Tank Destroyer Battalion’. Below you’ll find the article and my comments on it!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently Artificial Intelligence has been a lot in the news and as a Cloud Engineer, I frequently use it to help automate simple tasks in my work. Of course, I was also curious about the other options and thus I decided to ask it to teach me about the ‘614th Tank Destroyer Battalion’. Below you’ll find the article and my comments on it!</p>
<h2 id="putting-chatgpt-to-the-test">Putting ChatGPT to the test</h2>
<p>The following article has been created with the help of Artificial Intelligence, based upon the prompt ‘614th Tank Destroyer Battalion’:</p>
<p><em>The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion was an American tank destroyer unit that fought in World War II. The unit was formed in 1941 and trained at Camp Polk in Louisiana. The battalion was equipped with M10 tank destroyers, which were designed to take out enemy tanks at long range.</em><br/>
<em>The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion saw combat in several major campaigns, including the Battle of the Bulge and the Rhineland campaign. The unit was known for its ability to take out enemy tanks and armored vehicles, and was credited with destroying dozens of enemy tanks during the war.</em><br/>
<em>After the war, the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion was deactivated and its members returned home. Today, the unit is remembered for its bravery and service during World War II, and for its role in helping to defeat the Axis powers.</em></p>
<img alt="An image of a 3-inch gun of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion. Around it are several soldiers of the 614th TD Bn." loading="lazy" width="2635" height="1999" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2F614.652d4b4c.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p><em>(Image is in the public domain. Courtesy of National Archives and Records Administration.)</em></p>
<p>At first glance, the article might seem like a decent summary of the battalion’s history, but once you dive deeper into the material, you discover a lot of errors. In that sense, it’s not unusual, because the article is a recreation of what the AI had at its disposal and not a historically accurate rendering of the historical past.</p>
<p><em>The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion was an American tank destroyer unit that fought in World War II. The unit was formed in 1941 and trained at Camp Polk in Louisiana. The battalion was equipped with M10 tank destroyers, which were designed to take out enemy tanks at long range.</em></p>
<p>Indeed, the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion was an American unit and it did fight in the Second World War. However, the battalion was activated on 25 July 2942 at Camp Carson, Colorado. The battalion was equipped with the towed 3-inch M5 Gun, not with the M10 gun motor carriage.</p>
<p><em>The 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion saw combat in several major campaigns, including the Battle of the Bulge and the Rhineland campaign. The unit was known for its ability to take out enemy tanks and armored vehicles, and was credited with destroying dozens of enemy tanks during the war.</em></p>
<p>Indeed, it fought in several major campaigns, including the Rhineland Campaign. However, it didn’t fight in the Battle of the Bugle. Likewise, the unit is mostly known for the Battle of Climbach, where Third Platoon, C Company, earned the Presidential Unit Citation. The 614th TD also fought in the Northern France, Ardennes-Alsace, and Central Europe campaigns.</p>
<p><em>After the war, the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion was deactivated and its members returned home. Today, the unit is remembered for its bravery and service during World War II, and for its role in helping to defeat the Axis powers.</em></p>
<p>Naturally, once the war was over, many units were deactivated and their members returned home. The 614th TD did fight bravely, as is testified by the white soldiers they fought alongside, but is it still remembered for its service during the Second World War? The soldiers of the 103rd Infantry Division, to which the 614th TD was attached from December 1944 to May 1945 do indeed remember them, but outside of it, the 614th TD is relatively unknown. Several attempts are being made to change this, including (but not limited to!) sharing photographs or film clips of the movie, as well as articles in a variety of outlets.</p>
<p>At present, it looks like the field of AI will not yet make historians redundant. Indeed, AI can make the gathering of information easier. It can also be used to process large amounts of data. However, the closer you get to the source material, the more important human interactions and their appreciation become. People can lie, boast, misrepresent, diminish, exaggerate, remember, and misremember in the source material. As a historian, you need to judge, select and value sources, which is something that AI and automation cannot do. Thus, history will be one of the fields that will need human oversight for a long time to come. It’s good to know that we will not be redundant for a long time yet!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Film footage of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/film-footage-of-the-614th-tank-destroyer-battalion</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/film-footage-of-the-614th-tank-destroyer-battalion</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In the National Archives and Records Administration is a movie clip depicting soldiers of the 95 Infantry Division. At the moment of filming, the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion was attached to this unit and as you might have guessed, indeed, the soldiers of the 614th TD were also filmed! Finally I've managed to gain access to this clip and now I can share it with you.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This time I got something special to share! In the National Archives and Records Administration is a movie clip depicting soldiers of the 95 Infantry Division. At the moment of filming, the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion was attached to this unit and as you might have guessed, indeed, the soldiers of the 614th TD were also filmed! Finally I&#x27;ve managed to gain access to this clip and now I can share it with you.</p>
<img alt="a frame taken from the clip showing soldiers of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion eating chow." loading="lazy" width="1920" height="1080" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 500px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Featingchow.a692044b.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p>A still taken from the movie, showing soldiers of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion
eating chow.</p>
<h2 id="finally-found">Finally found!</h2>
<p>After a lot of research, I&#x27;ve managed to track down the appropriate reel and get it digitized. As far as I know, it&#x27;s the only film footage showing soldiers of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion during the Second World War. The clip shows soldiers of the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion lining a fox hole with straw, eating chow, digging a trench and guarding two reconnaissance M-20 Scout Cars. In between, there is a fragment showing soldiers of the 95th Infantry Divsion to which the 614th Tank Destroyer Battalion was attached at that time. The movie was made on 30 November 1944 in France.</p>
<h2 id="watch-it-online">Watch it online!</h2>
<p>The fragments featuring the soldiers of the 614th TD are available online.</p>
<div class="aspect-video w-full overflow-hidden rounded-md"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y7JqLgQ4CKw" class="h-full w-full" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<p>If the clip doesn&#x27;t show, you can also watch it <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y7JqLgQ4CKw">here</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Translating Wagevier his memoirs - Fighting for Napoleon his Army in Russia]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/wagevier-memoirs</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/wagevier-memoirs</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The past year I’ve been working on several projects. One of these projects, at which I’ve hinted several times, is the translation of Carel Jacob Wagevier’s memoir. As an officer in the Dutch 125th Regiment of the Line he joined the Russian campaign of 1812. During this campaign he fought in combat and was eventually taken prisoner.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The past year I’ve been working on several projects. One of these projects, at which I’ve hinted several times, is the translation of Carel Jacob Wagevier’s memoir. As an officer in the Dutch 125th Regiment of the Line he joined the Russian campaign of 1812. During this campaign he fought in combat and was eventually taken prisoner.</p>
<img alt="the cover of the book Fighting for Napoleon&#x27;s Army in Russia originally written in Dutch by C. J. Wagevier and translated by Samuel de Korte." loading="lazy" width="404" height="601" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 500px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FFighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia.ab0cfe5a.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p>The cover of the book</p>
<p>His captivity is marked with joy and sorrow, which he writes about diligently. He meets new friends, while losing several old ones. He’s a good observer and he writes eloquently about the sights and his experiences. It has been a fascinating book and it created the spark that eventually led to this translation. I strove to keep Wagevier’s voice as authentic as possible and I hope that the reader will derive as much joy from it as I had in creating this translation.</p>
<p>The book will published in June 2023, but if you are already excited, you can pre-order it on the site of <a href="https://www.pen-and-sword.co.uk/Fighting-for-Napoleons-Army-in-Russia-Hardback/p/23465">Pen and Sword</a> already.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How three black Americans captured 15 Germans]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/three-black-americans</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/three-black-americans</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[While doing historical research, you sometimes come across little gems. I recently came across an article in the Jackson Advocate of 22 July 1944, titled 3 Signal Corpsmen Capture 15 Germans in Short Order, that I wanted to share with you.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While doing historical research, you sometimes come across little gems. I recently came across an article in the Jackson Advocate of 22 July 1944, titled 3 Signal Corpsmen Capture 15 Germans in Short Order, that I wanted to share with you.</p>
<h2 id="army-serice-forces">Army Serice Forces</h2>
<p>During the Second World War, the American Army was segregated. Units were established based upon race and black Americans predominately served in support units. The Signal Corps is part of the Army Service Forces and many black Americans served in these units. Since they were often relegated to second-line duties, the black Americans infrequently encountered enemies in their line of duty.</p>
<p>A black American linesman during the Second World War. Photograph is in the public domain.</p>
<h2 id="infrequently-in-combat">Infrequently in Combat</h2>
<p>An exception happened in June or July 1944 in France, where three linesmen captured 15 Germans. Although it’s a minor encounter in the course of the war, it gives a glimpse into the experiences of black American soldiers during the Second World War. The article is added in its entirety below.</p>
<img alt="A black American linesman during the Second World War." loading="lazy" width="945" height="1175" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 200px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flinesman.dfada811.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p>A black American linesman during the Second World War. Photograph is in the public domain.</p>
<h2 id="3-signal-corpsmen-capture-15-germans-in-short-order">3 Signal Corpsmen Capture 15 Germans in Short Order</h2>
<h3 id="with-allied-forces-in-france-anp">WITH ALLIED FORCES IN FRANCE (ANP)</h3>
<p>The capture of 15 Germans by three [black Americans] of the army signal corps recently rates as the foremost news of this section. Those involved in the capture were Cpl. Bernard P. Henderson, 28, of New York City; Cpl. Percy E. Cox, Jr., 28, Petersburg, Va.; and Cpl. Allie W. Campbell, 26, Planes, Virginia.<br/>
When Cpl. Cox, who is a linesman, went to the top of a 30-foot pole to do a repair job, he happened to look down, he saw a German helmet moving in the bushes beneath him. Cox lost no time reaching the ground. He described his decent down the pole as “Burning the pole.” When he reached the ground, he yelled to Henderson, who was 30 yards away. Henderson ran to where Cox stood, dropped and rolled over, at the same time pulling his carbine, a lesson he learned in basic training.<br/>
“There is a German there,” Cox shouted to Henderson, indicating the Nazi’s position by pointing his finger. Henderson began shooting where Cox pointed and the German popped up with his hands in the air. Henderson fired again and three more Germans jumped up, muttering something the boys could not understand: another shot brought three more Nazis: again Henderson fired, this time five Germans showed with upraised hands. The fifth and last shot brought the total surrender to 15, all looking frightened and pitiful.</p>
<h3 id="driver-comes-up">DRIVER COMES UP</h3>
<p>By this time, Campbell, who was the truck driver, heard the shots. He grabbed his tommy gun and ran to where Cox and Henderson were.
Since they were out of ammunition, they were glad he lost no time in coming to their rescue. They told him what had happened and he immediately wanted to prowl for more Germans but they finally agreed to pack to 15 “Jerries” in the truck and take them to headquarters as quickly as possible.<br/>
The boys had carried out their duties in excellent fashion. They had searched the prisoners and confiscated valuable papers. Henderson and Cox did guard duty while Campbell drove the prisoners to the provost office. The commanding officer was surprised to see the 15 Nazis being ushered into his presence. Lt. Charles A. Gray, Audubon, N. J., extended congratulations.</p>
<h3 id="proud-of-men">PROUD OF MEN</h3>
<p>“The three boys executed the act admirably,” said Lt. Gray, a platoon officer, “just as if they were infantry men and trained for the job. They acted like all soldiers should act and one of the dominating features of it was that they were not boastful.’’ Lt. Gray said he is extremely proud of the men in general for they are making an outstanding contribution to the cause.
The commanding officer, Major Thomas J. Quan, Worchesber, Mass., beamed with excitement. He is pleased at the distinction the three heroes brought to the battalion.<br/>
Bernard P. Henderson is the son of a woman candidate for the 19th Assembly of New York, Mrs. Anna H. Hughes. Henderson’s wife, Mae, and daughter, Gloria, 6, are now in Washington, D. C. Before entering the army, the operated a switchboard at the Woodside Hotel in Manhattan. He is a graduate of Cooper Junior High School.
Cpl. Percy E. Cox is the son of Mrs. Percy Cox of Petersburg, Va. He was employed by the Johnson Taxi company before he entered Peabody High School in Petersburg. A native of Plains, Va.,
Cpl. Allie W. Campbell is the son of Mrs. Lucille Campbell. He is a graduate of the Posters Fork Public school. All three are classified as linesmen and had broken up into sections when the capture of the 15 Germans occurred.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Historical projects and 2023: what to expect?]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/the-focus-for-2023</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/the-focus-for-2023</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Since the new year started recently, I thought it might be interesting to provide some insight into the projects that I am currently working on.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="historical-projects-and-2023-what-to-expect">Historical projects and 2023: what to expect?</h2>
<p>Since the new year started recently, I thought it might be interesting to provide some insight into the projects that I am currently working on. Of course, I’ll continue working on sharing the experiences of black American soldiers during the Second World War. However, there’s a small historical detour along the way in 2023. The three projects I’m focusing on right now are the Tuskegee Airmen, the translation of the memoirs of C. J. Wagevier, and the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion.</p>
<h2 id="tuskegee-airmen">Tuskegee Airmen</h2>
<p>The history of the 332nd Fighter Group is well known. The famous ‘Red Tails’, black American pilots that escorted bombers of the Fifteenth American Air Force during their campaigns over Europe, have been written about frequently and they are used as an example of how black Americans contributed to the Second World War. However, the Tuskegee Airmen were much more than this fighter group. Some Tuskegee Airmen served as artillery liaisons in the Pacific Theater, while 477th Bombardment Group fought their own battles against their own racist countrymen in America.</p>
<h2 id="the-translation-of-wageviers-memoir">The translation of Wagevier’s memoir</h2>
<p>In 1812, C. J. Wagevier was one of the Dutch officers that went with Napoleon to Russia. This campaign was a disaster and decimated the French army. Serving in the 125th Regiment of the Line, Wagevier was taken prisoner and spent two years as a prisoner of war in Russia. Upon his return, he wrote about his experiences in the campaign, captivity, and release. His memoirs were published in 1820 and I translated them from Dutch to English. Wagevier is an eloquent writer and his experiences deserve much more recognition than they have received so far. I have tried to retain his style as much as possible.</p>
<img alt="Soldiers of the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion watch the skies." figcaption="The 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion." loading="lazy" width="1024" height="828" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 200px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fimage-5.b90230af.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<p>The 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion. Photograph is taken from the National Archives and Records Administration.</p>
<h2 id="the-452nd-anti-aircraft-artillery-battalion">The 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion</h2>
<p>I’m in the process of acquiring historical materials related to the 452nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalion. This unit was one of the few segregated American Anti-Aircraft Artillery Battalions that heavily participated in the Second World War. Throughout its active service, it destroyed 68 planes and had 19 shared kills. Currently, I’ve got a pile of historical material in a box, as the two projects above demand my immediate attention, but I look forward to digging into this material. Who knows what there is to uncover about the history of this fascinating unit?</p>
<h2 id="looking-forward-to-more">Looking forward to more!</h2>
<p>That’s all for now. Beyond doubt, there will be other projects that I will pick up during the year, but these are my main focus. I’ll keep you updated about the progress and look forward to what this year will bring!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: The Kármán Line by Dennis Hopeless]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-karman-line</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-karman-line</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The earth is dying. Five astronauts are working in space for a potential Mars colonization program. All of the astronauts are specialists in a different field.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Title: The Kármán Line<br/>
Creator: Dennis Hopeless<br/>
Published: 2023</em></p>
<h2 id="thank-you-netgalley-and-the-publisher">Thank you Netgalley and the Publisher</h2>
<p>I’d like to thank Netgalley and the publisher for giving me the chance to read an advance copy in exchange for an honest review. The comic book is decent and I enjoyed reading through it. The artwork was fitting and the characters were okay.</p>
<h2 id="earth-is-dying-and-social-media">Earth is Dying and Social Media</h2>
<p>The earth is dying. Five astronauts are working in space for a potential Mars colonization program. All of the astronauts are specialists in a different field. In addition to the usual space occupations, there is also a social media influencer. She was sent up there to ensure that the ratings are kept up and that the mission is funded by the viewers. However, when the five astronauts each receive a variation of the order “RETURN TO EARTH”, chaos ensues and each person tries to make it back. Meanwhile, the camera continue to broadcast.</p>
<h2 id="social-media-commentary">Social Media Commentary</h2>
<p>Mostly, I interpreted the comic as a social media critique. After all, the astronauts each receive a slightly different message and interpret it differently. In a way, it’s a commentary on social media, where each of us is separated from another by the news or ‘news’ that we consume. Since the news often reports on events happening far away from us, we have to trust that the news is accurate and reliable. What if the news is faked? What if the person sharing the message was more concerned with commercial issues than with reliability? Social media, as a mobilization tool, has the power to create and to destroy. The comic did get me thinking about these issues and the fact that it provided a bit of social commentary elevates it to a higher status than comic books that merely provide entertainment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: My Life Among Humans by Jed McGowan]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-life-among-humans</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-life-among-humans</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[My Life Among Humans is a humorous graphic novel. It provides a quick and entertaining read. It’s an endearing story and I greatly enjoyed reading it.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Title: My Life Among Humans<br/>
Author: Jed McGowan<br/>
Published: 2023</em></p>
<h2 id="thank-you-netgalley-and-the-publisher">Thank you Netgalley and the Publisher</h2>
<p>Through Netgalley I was given the chance to read an advance copy in exchange for an honest review. My Life Among Humans is a humorous graphic novel. It provides a quick and entertaining read. It’s an endearing story and I greatly enjoyed reading it.</p>
<h2 id="an-alien-worker-on-earth">An Alien Worker on Earth</h2>
<p>An alien worker is sent to Earth to observe humans. It’s task is to report back to its manager, which wants to have clean data. This eventually results in a dilemma, after the alien is discovered and takes over the subjects it is supposed to be observing. From this point on, the manager tries to cover up its error as well as to prevent the other humans from discovering its existence. Eventually, the manager arrives on Earth to discover what is going on.</p>
<img alt="The alien around whom the story is centered." caption="The alien around whom the story is centered." loading="lazy" width="631" height="508" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 200px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Flifeamonghumans.14e9da7e.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<figcaption align="center"><b>&quot;The alien around whom the story is centered.&quot;</b></figcaption>
<h2 id="alien-invader-horror-story">Alien Invader Horror Story</h2>
<p>In a sense, it’s a classical ‘alien invader horror story’. An unknown force is slowly taking over people in a town and a small group of humans need to find out what is happening and prevent others from suffering a similar fate. The twist is that the story is observed from the point of view of the alien and that the alien has no hostile intent. It just wants to do its job and stay out of trouble.</p>
<h2 id="pleasantly-surprised">Pleasantly Surprised</h2>
<p>Surprisingly, the comic has a depth that I had not expected at first. The alien has a larger background than anticipated. Another thing I liked was the humor! For example, when the alien tries to mimic being a human, it results in the necessary mistakes. There are some references to being a corporate employee and the accompanying issues that I could appreciate. It’s a easily accessible story and provides a light-hearted reading.</p>
<p>Overall, I enjoyed reading this book.</p>
<p>If you are considering buying the book, please use the link below. By ordering through the link below, I may be eligible for a small commission, at no additional costs to you.</p>
<p><a href="https://amzn.to/3WnWmB9">Amazon.com</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review of Terror World by Cath Lauria]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-terror-world</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-terror-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Scientist Dizzie Drexler is sent out, together with a crew, to uncover an abandoned spaceship on a remote planet. The crew consists of a telepathic centaur, two thieves Grayson and Mason, and an alien bodyguard Divak. The expedition is funded by the secretive alien Ix-Nix-Six. Once there, horror ensues and zombies quickly appear.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Title: Terror World: A Zombicide Invader Novel<br/>
Author: Cath Lauria<br/>
Published: 2023</em></p>
<h2 id="thank-you-netgalley-and-full-disclosure">Thank you Netgalley and full disclosure</h2>
<p>Through Netgalley I was given the chance to read an advance copy in exchange for an honest review. For full disclosure, I have never played zombicide, the board game series that inspired these stories. With this in mind, I might not have been the audience that this book is targeting. That being said, if you are the audience that this book is aiming for, then you’re certainly in for a ride! The cover and title ‘Terror World’, already give an impression of what you can expect and the book delivers exactly.</p>
<h2 id="an-abandoned-spaceship-on-a-remote-planet">An Abandoned Spaceship on a Remote Planet</h2>
<p>Scientist Dizzie Drexler is sent out, together with a crew, to uncover an abandoned spaceship on a remote planet. The crew consists of a telepathic centaur, two thieves Grayson and Mason, and an alien bodyguard Divak. The expedition is funded by the secretive alien Ix-Nix-Six. Once there, horror ensues and zombies quickly appear.</p>
<h2 id="aimed-at-a-specific-audience">Aimed at a Specific Audience</h2>
<p>This is the kind of story that you need to be looking for: people stranded on a remote planet, horror, zombies, science fiction. It’s written for fans of these board games. The story really gets underway about 2/5th of the book. Overall, it’s a satisfactory story. It is quite entertaining if this is a particular type of fiction you’re looking for. The story reads easily and there’s a diverse cast of characters.</p>
<h2 id="personal-opinion">Personal Opinion</h2>
<p>There are references to the alien races featured in the board game zombicide invader, while also providing more background for several of the alien races and organizations involved. Some of the characters are more developed than others. Personally, I had hoped for more content from Mason, a cyborg. Each of his limbs has his own mind and there are even a few chapters written from the perspective of Lefty, his left arm. The only drawback is that I would have liked more closure from the ending. Several of the questions are left unanswered, although it could be the potential setup for a sequel.</p>
<p>Overall, I enjoyed reading the book.</p>
<p>If you are considering buying the book, please use the link below. By ordering through the link below, I may be eligible for a small commission, at no additional costs to you.</p>
<p><a href="https://amzn.to/3BIKlxD">Amazon.com</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review of The Dunwich Horror by H. P. Lovecraft]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-dunwich</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-dunwich</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Dunwich horror was one of my first forays into the work of H.P. Lovecraft. I have read some other horror fiction before, but this was my first book set in the Cthulhu Mythos universe. I’ve read it recently and thoroughly enjoyed it!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Title: The Dunwich horror<br/>
Author: H. P. Lovecraft<br/>
Published: 1929</em></p>
<p>The Dunwich horror was one of my first forays into the work of H.P. Lovecraft. I have read some other horror fiction before, but this was my first book set in the Cthulhu Mythos universe. I’ve read it recently and thoroughly enjoyed it!</p>
<h2 id="wilbur-whateley">Wilbur Whateley</h2>
<p>The story is set in Dunwich, a small village, where a mysterious child lives. He’s raised by his mother and his grandfather, Old Whateley. Old Whateley is a sorcerer and he teaches his grandchild about forbidden rituals. This child, Wilbur Whateley, ages rapidly and is shunned by the local inhabitants. The house that they live in is expanded several times and although the family often buys new animals, their herd never grows.</p>
<h2 id="alone-in-the-house">Alone in the House</h2>
<p>After the death of his family, Wilbur continues to live in the house alone. It becomes obvious there&#x27;s more to him and the house than meets the eye. Wilbur eventually runs into some problems, but he does not have the appropriate tools to do so.</p>
<h2 id="the-dunwich-horror">The Dunwich Horror</h2>
<p>Since a magical book is needed, Wilbur tries to acquire it legally through a library, but is unable to do so. Because of this, he tries to do it illegally and is killed in the process. At this point, the focus of the story shifts, centering on the efforts of three professors to uncover the mysterious origins of Wilbur Whateley and the strange events surrounding the family’s house in Dunwich. Eventually it turns out that an invisible monster lives in the house, which escapes and rampages around the countryside, before confronted by the three professors and a local posse. As for how this ends, you’ll have to read the book yourself.</p>
<h2 id="available-on-project-gutenberg">Available on Project Gutenberg</h2>
<p>The story is quick and fun to read. Lovecraft masterfully sets the stage and knows well how to keep the reader engaged. You want to keep reading! Highly recommended to read for those interested in horror-mystery stories.  The story is available for free at Project Gutenberg.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/50133">Project Gutenberg</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review of The Notebooks of Captain Coignet]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-coignet</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-coignet</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[At a first glance, the subtitle of the book gives away immediately what this book is about. Captain Coignet was a soldier of the French Empire and served for sixteen years throughout various campaigns and battles. In total Coignet served for more than 16 years in the French army and he was involved in 16 campaigns. He fought in Austria, Spain, Italy, Prussia and Russia, and he wrote about his experiences.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Title: The narrative of Captain Coignet: Soldier of the Empire<br/>
Author: Jean-Roch Coignet</p>
<p>At a first glance, the subtitle of the book gives away immediately what this book is about. Captain Coignet was a soldier of the French Empire and served for sixteen years throughout various campaigns and battles. In total Coignet served for more than 16 years in the French army and he was involved in 16 campaigns. He fought in Austria, Spain, Italy, Prussia and Russia, and he wrote about his experiences.</p>
<img alt="A photograph of Jean-Roch Coignet." loading="lazy" width="153" height="241" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fcoignet.16b34b35.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<h2 id="vivid-descriptions-of-the-battles">Vivid Descriptions of the Battles</h2>
<p>Initially, Coignet starts with his unhappy youth and the decision to become a soldier. Remarkable is that Coignet has served as a common soldier and rose to the rank of officer. He also did not learn to read and write until he was 33 years old, when it was necessary for a promotion. As a young man, he survived several of the bloodiest battles in European history, including the retreat from Russia (1812) and the battle of Waterloo (1815). He leaves an vivid description of the battles and countries that he has visited.</p>
<h2 id="serving-in-the-imperial-guard">Serving in the Imperial Guard</h2>
<p>For his bravery at the battle of Montebello Coignet was marked for service in the Imperial Guard, where he served for the remainder of his time in the army. His memoirs range from combat that he has experienced, as well as experiences in camps, at parties, or while in garrison. This sometimes results in funny situations. When asked about taking a napkin after a dinner, Coignet gives it back and excuses himself by saying that in the enemy’s country it is seen as a sign of neglect when you don’t take something from a dinner party.
More than once, Coignet is lucky to survive. During the battle of Marengo he only managed to survive, because he discarded all his possessions and grabbed the tail of a passing horse. He managed to hold on for a few paces, but it was enough to get him to safety. He then acquires a new gun and retreats with the rest of the army.<br/>
Coignet frequently writes about the courage that he witnesses, whether it is from his comrades or his superiors. More than once he comments on how a soldier or officer behaved bravely in combat. As he writes, “it may be said in praise of Marshal Ney that he kept the enemy at bay at Kowno [currently Kaunas in Lithuania] by his own bravery. I saw him take a gun and five men and face the enemy.”</p>
<h2 id="published-in-1850">Published in 1850</h2>
<p>After retiring from the army, he settled in Auxerre, married and ran a shop together with his wife. In 1848, his wife, to whom he had been married for more than 30 years, passed away and he was left alone. At the age of 72, he was too old to start over and he felt despondent. In writing he found an outlet. In his writings, he could preserve the experiences of his youth, his campaigns and the things that he has witnessed. Coignet also ends his book with lesson, “Let [the parents] use every effort to have their children taught to read and write, and to train them well. This is the best inheritance, and is easily supported.”</p>
<h2 id="available-for-free">Available for free</h2>
<p>Being written in rough French, the memoirs were later edited by Loredan Larchay, who rewrote it to make it more accessible. This version was later translated in English and other languages and available for online. In the links below, you can download an English and a French version for free.</p>
<p><a href="https://archive.org/details/narrativeofcapta00coig/page/192/mode/2up">English</a><br/>
<a href="https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/author/42075">French</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The necessity of an e-reader when traveling]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/ereader-necessary</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/ereader-necessary</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The past year I have traveled extensively and I wasn’t limited to being in one place. Due to my frequent moving, I needed to carry few possessions with me. As the space was limited, I needed to consider the items that I really wanted to take along, regardless of where I was. There’s one item that I always took along with me, regardless of where I was traveling: an e-reader.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The past year I have traveled extensively and I wasn’t limited to being in one place. Due to my frequent moving, I needed to carry few possessions with me. As the space was limited, I needed to consider the items that I really wanted to take along, regardless of where I was. There’s one item that I always took along with me, regardless of where I was traveling: an e-reader.</p>
<h2 id="essential-for-traveling">Essential for Traveling</h2>
<p>While traveling around Europe, staying in Portugal or Italy, I needed to bring all my material possessions with me. At first, I thought that I could read from my laptop for leisure, but this turned out different than I thought. I had hoped that by not bringing books, I saved space for other stuff. Reading from an internet page is a bit different than reading from a physical page. Buying a book in a store was also not a good option, as I would need to leave the book behind when I moved on again. Another option was buying an e-reader. Since then, I’ve read several books on my e-reader. These vary from books for leisure to (historical) research material.</p>
<h2 id="flexibility-in-a5-format">Flexibility in A5-format</h2>
<p>Actually, all benefits of an e-reader have to do with flexibility, which manifests itself in different ways. Most e-readers are relatively thin, less than a centimeter, are smaller than half of a A4 paper. They are thinner than most books. Since the e-readers are so small, they take up little space and do not weigh a lot. Meanwhile, you can easily store hundreds or thousands of books on it.<br/>
The most common e-readers have a storage of 8 GB, which equals to approximately 6000 books. These numbers can vary, depending on whether you are reading comic books, large PDF files or just smaller text versions. Regardless, the memory of an e-reader is large enough to rival the catalogue of a small library. You can always carry your favorite writers with you. You are not just limited to that one book that you have brought along, but can pick one of the many books on your device. Is your current read not interesting or fitting for your mood? You can easily start another one.<br/>
If you are looking for a new book to read, you can order it on your computer and share it with your device. If your e-reader is connected to the internet, you can immediately access the store and look for an interesting book. With a press of the button, they are on your device and you don’t need to wait until a package is delivered.</p>
<h2 id="additional-benefits">Additional Benefits</h2>
<p>There are some other factors that make e-readers so useful, depending on the type of e-reader. Not all of them are equipped with these features, so make sure these are on the device when you are planning on buying an e-reader.<br/>
Most e-readers have backlight, which makes them easy to read when there’s little daylight. You can easily read in bed or outside, even when there’s no light available. In most devices, it’s even possible to filter out the blue light, which can disturb your sleep.<br/>
Depending on the file, the letter format and font can easily be adjusted. With books the ink is set. While it’s not always necessary, there have been some books where the letters were so small, that I had to enlarge them to read the book properly.<br/>
Most readers are more resilient than in the past. Some water splashes will not immediately result of the device. You can even put a sleeve around the e-reader for additional protection.<br/>
Lastly, the e-readers can last for quite some time. Most devices will last at least a week on a single charge. Recharging goes fast and is usually done in a matter of minutes rather than hours.</p>
<h2 id="all-benefits">All Benefits</h2>
<p>Is an e-reader a necessity while traveling? Absolutely! The e-reader takes up little space, but is incredibly useful. The device takes up little space and contains so many books that you’ll have countless hours of reading on it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review of Memoirs of Sergeant Bourgogne, 1812-1813 by Adrien Bourgogne]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-bourgogne</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/review-bourgogne</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In June 1812 Napoleon Bonaparte attacked Imperial Russia with his armies. More than half a million men and women were gathered for this operation. However, the invasion turned out different than Napoleon expected. After Napoleon had reached Moscow, it turned out that his supply lines were overstretched and his army was unprepared to spend the winter in Russia. He made the fatal decision to retreat. During this journey countless men and women lost their lives.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In June 1812 Napoleon Bonaparte attacked Imperial Russia with his armies. More than half a million men and women were gathered for this operation. However, the invasion turned out different than Napoleon expected. After Napoleon had reached Moscow, it turned out that his supply lines were overstretched and his army was unprepared to spend the winter in Russia. He made the fatal decision to retreat. During this journey countless men and women lost their lives.</p>
<img alt="A drawing of Adrien Bourgogne." loading="lazy" width="191" height="244" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Fbourgogne.d79dc664.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<h2 id="a-historical-event">A Historical Event</h2>
<p>Among the survivors, many quickly realized what a major historical event this had been. Sergeant Adrien Bourgogne (1785-1867), who served with the Imperial Guard, has written about this horrible journey. Together with Napoleon he went to Russia and finally reached Moscow, where he made himself comfortable in the scorched city. Finally, the order was given to retreat and together with his unit he started to travel westwards.</p>
<h2 id="enduring-hardships">Enduring Hardships</h2>
<p>In the beginning everything seemed to be alright, but quickly problems developed. Discipline lessened. Troops deserted or went plundering. There was too little food. To make matters even more complicated, the temperature started to drop. While enduring all these hardships and with the help of strangers and comrades, Bourgogne managed to survive the journey with the remnants of the French army.</p>
<h2 id="published-in-1853">Published in 1853</h2>
<p>In 1813 Bourgogne, who had risen to the rank of sublieutenant, was made a prisoner of war and while in captivity, he realized what a remarkable event happened the previous year. From that moment, he started working on his memoir, but didn’t finish it. He returned to France after peace was declared and took over his father’s clothing store. It wasn’t until 1853 that he finally finished his book.</p>
<h2 id="available-on-project-gutenberg">Available on Project Gutenberg</h2>
<p>In his memoir the terrible circumstances in which the men and women of the French army found themselves become obvious. Hunted by the enemy, suffering from the cold and hunger, they needed help from others and luck to survive. A kind passing stranger or a good friend could make a difference between life and death in terrible moments. One of the reasons why Bourgogne managed to survive was due to the help of his comrades. It&#x27;s a captivating read and I highly recommend it.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/59489">English</a><br/>
<a href="https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/11176">French</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What a wonderful world we live in]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/articles/what-a-wonderful-world</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/articles/what-a-wonderful-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Frequently technology is featured in the news and not always in a positive way. According to some people it would influence our lives too much. We would be too dependent on technology or it would make us anti-social. Personally, I doubt it, because technology allows us to be more connected than ever before. Happily, I’ll share some personal experiences.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Frequently technology is featured in the news and not always in a positive way. According to some people it would influence our lives too much. We would be too dependent on technology or it would make us anti-social. Personally, I doubt it, because technology allows us to be more connected than ever before. Happily, I’ll share some personal experiences.</p>
<img alt="A photograph of the boardgame Catan." loading="lazy" width="8256" height="3048" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" class="aspect-square rotate-0 rounded-2xl bg-stone-100 object-cover dark:bg-stone-800" style="color:transparent" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 32rem, 20rem" srcSet="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=16&amp;q=75 16w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=32&amp;q=75 32w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=48&amp;q=75 48w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=64&amp;q=75 64w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=96&amp;q=75 96w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=128&amp;q=75 128w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=256&amp;q=75 256w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=384&amp;q=75 384w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=640&amp;q=75 640w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=750&amp;q=75 750w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=828&amp;q=75 828w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=1080&amp;q=75 1080w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;q=75 1200w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75 1920w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=2048&amp;q=75 2048w, /_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75 3840w" src="/_next/image?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2FCatan.01a603e8.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75"/>
<h2 id="catan-online">Catan Online</h2>
<p>For a while I lived in Italy and Portugal. Geographically, I was around a thousand kilometers removed from my friends. This distance made it impossible to visit each other in person. However, while each of us was in his own home, we spoke with each other through our phones and played the same game on our computers. One of my two friends then remarked that it was quite unusual, we were so far apart, yet it did not feel as such. And indeed, it’s remarkable, because our current technology allows us to be more connected with people than ever before.</p>
<h2 id="sharing-information">Sharing information</h2>
<p>In the distant past, information was shared by sending messages. Information travelled with the speed of the carrier. According to the situation, this could go faster or slower. For example, think of the message about the victory at Marathon in 490 B.C. According to the legend, a soldier ran all the way from Marathon to Athens to report on the victory in battle. Later it became more common to send written messages, allowing a single person to carry over more than one message, but they still needed to be brought physically from one location to another. You still depended on the human middleman and the available transportation. Although technological advancements could transport the letters faster - for example, by bringing it somewhere by boat, train, or plane -, sharing information was much more rapid in the digital area. A middleman was no longer necessary and an email can go across the globe in less than a second. These are just examples, because there are plenty of other ways to get in contact with people and to feel connected. In my case, I was around a thousand kilometers distant from my family and friends, but I did not experience loneliness.</p>
<h2 id="the-digital-world">The digital world</h2>
<p>Due to the covid-19 pandemic, digitalization has been pushed forward worldwide. Willingly or not, everything and everyone had to adapt. Work became different. Education became different. You needed to adapt. The whole of the Netherlands, if not the entire world, was hurled into the digital revolution. The result is that there are now more ways than ever before to keep in touch. Although the way of connecting might be different, because instead of gathering in a group in a physical location, we gather in a digital location, you can share stories immediately. Instead of telling them in person, you can share voice messages and stay informed of each other’s lives. You are still connected with other. Chatting, messaging, (video)calling, emailing, digital meetings, the options are endless. There is a digital word to explore and you can connect to the whole word. I’m curious to see what the future will bring!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>samueldekorte@gmail.com (Samuel de Korte)</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>